{
    "title": "Elasticity and Its Application",
    "icon": "<svg xmlns=\"http://www.w3.org/2000/svg\" class=\"h-8 w-8\" fill=\"none\" viewBox=\"0 0 24 24\" stroke=\"currentColor\" stroke-width=\"2\"><path stroke-linecap=\"round\" stroke-linejoin=\"round\" d=\"M19 11H5m14 0a2 2 0 012 2v6a2 2 0 01-2 2H5a2 2 0 01-2-2v-6a2 2 0 012-2m14 0V9a2 2 0 00-2-2M5 11V9a2 2 0 012-2m0 0V5a2 2 0 012-2h6a2 2 0 012 2v2M7 7h10\" /></svg>",
    "sectors": {
        "sector1": {
            "title": "Multiple Choice",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "q_num": 1,
                    "topic": "Multiple Choice",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In general, elasticity is a measure of",
                    "options": [
                        "the extent to which advances in technology are adopted by producers.",
                        "the extent to which a market is competitive.",
                        "how firms' profits respond to changes in market prices.",
                        "how much buyers and sellers respond to changes in market conditions."
                    ],
                    "answer": "how much buyers and sellers respond to changes in market conditions.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 2,
                    "topic": "Multiple Choice",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Elasticity is",
                    "options": [
                        "a measure of how much buyers and sellers respond to changes in market conditions.",
                        "the study of how the allocation of resources affects economic well-being.",
                        "the maximum amount that a buyer will pay for a good.",
                        "the value of everything a seller must give up to produce a good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "a measure of how much buyers and sellers respond to changes in market conditions.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 3,
                    "topic": "Multiple Choice",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When studying how some event or policy affects a market, elasticity provides information on the",
                    "options": [
                        "equity effects on the market by identifying the winners and losers.",
                        "magnitude of the effect on the market.",
                        "speed of adjustment of the market in response to the event or policy.",
                        "number of market participants who are directly affected by the event or policy."
                    ],
                    "answer": "magnitude of the effect on the market.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 4,
                    "topic": "Multiple Choice",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When studying how some event or policy affects a market, elasticity provides information on the",
                    "options": [
                        "government expenditures associated with the policy.",
                        "costs and benefits of the effect.",
                        "allocative efficiency of the effect.",
                        "direction and magnitude of the effect."
                    ],
                    "answer": "direction and magnitude of the effect.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 5,
                    "topic": "Multiple Choice",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "How does the concept of elasticity allow us to improve upon our understanding of supply and demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "Elasticity allows us to analyze supply and demand with greater precision than would be the case in the absence of the elasticity concept.",
                        "Elasticity provides us with a better rationale for statements such as \"an increase in x will lead to a decrease in y\" than we would have in the absence of the elasticity concept.",
                        "Without elasticity, we would not be able to address the direction in which price is likely to move in response to a surplus or a shortage.",
                        "Without elasticity, it is very difficult to assess the degree of competition within a market."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Elasticity allows us to analyze supply and demand with greater precision than would be the case in the absence of the elasticity concept.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 6,
                    "topic": "Multiple Choice",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When consumers face rising gasoline prices, they typically",
                    "options": [
                        "reduce their quantity demanded more in the long run than in the short run.",
                        "reduce their quantity demanded more in the short run than in the long run.",
                        "do not reduce their quantity demanded in the short run or the long run.",
                        "increase their quantity demanded in the short run but reduce their quantity demanded in the long run."
                    ],
                    "answer": "reduce their quantity demanded more in the long run than in the short run.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 7,
                    "topic": "Multiple Choice",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A 10 percent increase in gasoline prices reduces gasoline consumption by about",
                    "options": [
                        "6 percent after one year and 2.5 percent after five years.",
                        "2.5 percent after one year and 6 percent after five years.",
                        "10 percent after one year and 20 percent after five years.",
                        "0 percent after one year and 1 percent after five years."
                    ],
                    "answer": "2.5 percent after one year and 6 percent after five years.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 8,
                    "topic": "Multiple Choice",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements about the consumers' responses to rising gasoline prices is correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "About 10 percent of the long-run reduction in quantity demanded arises because people drive less and about 90 percent arises because they switch to more fuel-efficient cars.",
                        "About 90 percent of the long-run reduction in quantity demanded arises because people drive less and about 10 percent arises because they switch to more fuel-efficient cars.",
                        "About half of the long-run reduction in quantity demanded arises because people drive less and about half arises because they switch to more fuel-efficient cars.",
                        "Because gasoline is a necessity, consumers do not decrease their quantity demanded in either the short run or the long run."
                    ],
                    "answer": "About half of the long-run reduction in quantity demanded arises because people drive less and about half arises because they switch to more fuel-efficient cars.",
                    "explanation": ""
                }
            ]
        },
        "sector2": {
            "title": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "q_num": 1,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The price elasticity of demand measures how much",
                    "options": [
                        "quantity demanded responds to a change in price.",
                        "quantity demanded responds to a change in income.",
                        "price responds to a change in demand.",
                        "demand responds to a change in supply."
                    ],
                    "answer": "quantity demanded responds to a change in price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 1,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "3",
                    "options": [],
                    "answer": "",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 1,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-5. Using the midpoint method, when income equals $7,500, what is the price elasticity of demand between $16 and $20?",
                    "options": [
                        "0.56",
                        "0.75",
                        "1.33",
                        "1.80"
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.80",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 2,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The price elasticity of demand measures",
                    "options": [
                        "buyers' responsiveness to a change in the price of a good.",
                        "the extent to which demand increases as additional buyers enter the market.",
                        "how much more of a good consumers will demand when incomes rise.",
                        "the movement along a supply curve when there is a change in demand."
                    ],
                    "answer": "buyers' responsiveness to a change in the price of a good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 2,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "1",
                    "options": [],
                    "answer": "",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 2,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-5. Using the midpoint method, when income equals $5,000, what is the price elasticity of demand between $8 and $12?",
                    "options": [
                        "0.56",
                        "0.75",
                        "1.33",
                        "1.80"
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.56",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 3,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The price elasticity of demand for a good measures the willingness of",
                    "options": [
                        "consumers to buy less of the good as price rises.",
                        "consumers to avoid monopolistic markets in favor of competitive markets.",
                        "firms to produce more of a good as price rises.",
                        "firms to respond to the tastes of consumers."
                    ],
                    "answer": "consumers to buy less of the good as price rises.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 3,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-5. Using the midpoint method, at a price of $16, what is the income elasticity of demand when income rises from $5,000 to $10,000?",
                    "options": [
                        "0.00",
                        "0.50",
                        "1.00",
                        "1.50"
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.00",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 4,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements about the price elasticity of demand is correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "The price elasticity of demand for a good measures the willingness of buyers of the good to buy less of the good as its price increases.",
                        "Price elasticity of demand reflects the many economic, psychological, and social forces that shape consumer tastes.",
                        "Other things equal, if good x has close substitutes and good y does not have close substitutes, then the demand for good x will be more elastic than the demand for good y.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 4,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-5. Using the midpoint method, at a price of $8, what is the income elasticity of demand when income rises from $7,500 to $10,000?",
                    "options": [
                        "0.00",
                        "0.41",
                        "1.00",
                        "2.45"
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.00",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 5,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price of natural gas rises, when is the price elasticity of demand likely to be the highest?",
                    "options": [
                        "immediately after the price increase",
                        "one month after the price increase",
                        "three months after the price increase",
                        "one year after the price increase"
                    ],
                    "answer": "one year after the price increase",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 5,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-5. Using the midpoint method, at a price of $12, what is the income elasticity of demand when income rises from $5,000 to $10,000?",
                    "options": [
                        "0.00",
                        "0.41",
                        "1.00",
                        "2.45"
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.00",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 6,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price of gasoline rises, when is the price elasticity of demand likely to be the highest?",
                    "options": [
                        "immediately after the price increases",
                        "one month after the price increase",
                        "three months after the price increase",
                        "one year after the price increase"
                    ],
                    "answer": "one year after the price increase",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 6,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-6. Using the midpoint method, what is the income elasticity of demand for good X?",
                    "options": [
                        "-3.5",
                        "-0.29",
                        "0.29",
                        "3.5"
                    ],
                    "answer": "3.5",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 7,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price of milk rises, when is the price elasticity of demand likely to be the lowest?",
                    "options": [
                        "immediately after the price increase",
                        "one month after the price increase",
                        "three months after the price increase",
                        "one year after the price increase"
                    ],
                    "answer": "immediately after the price increase",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 7,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-6. Using the midpoint method, the income elasticity of demand for good Y is",
                    "options": [
                        "2.33, and good Y is a normal good.",
                        "-2.33, and good Y is an inferior good.",
                        "-0.43, and good Y is a normal good.",
                        "-0.43, and good Y is an inferior good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "-2.33, and good Y is an inferior good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 8,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Holding all other forces constant, when the price of gasoline rises, the number of gallons of gasoline demanded would fall substantially over a ten-year period because",
                    "options": [
                        "buyers tend to be much less sensitive to a change in price when given more time to react.",
                        "buyers tend to be much more sensitive to a change in price when given more time to react.",
                        "buyers will have substantially more real income over a ten-year period.",
                        "the quantity supplied of gasoline increases very little in response to an increase in the price of gasoline."
                    ],
                    "answer": "buyers tend to be much more sensitive to a change in price when given more time to react.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 8,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Last year, Shelley bought 6 pairs of designer jeans when her income was $40,000. This year, her income is $50,000, and she purchased 10 pairs of designer jeans. Holding other factors constant, it follows that Shelley",
                    "options": [
                        "considers designer jeans to be a necessity.",
                        "considers designer jeans to be an inferior good.",
                        "considers designer jeans to be a normal good.",
                        "has a low price elasticity of demand for jeans."
                    ],
                    "answer": "considers designer jeans to be a normal good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 9,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is not a determinant of the price elasticity of demand for a good?",
                    "options": [
                        "the time horizon",
                        "the steepness or flatness of the supply curve for the good",
                        "the definition of the market for the good",
                        "the availability of substitutes for the good"
                    ],
                    "answer": "the steepness or flatness of the supply curve for the good",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 9,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Last year, Carolyn bought 6 pairs of earrings when her income was $40,000. This year, her income is $52,000, and she purchased 7 pairs of earrings. Holding other factors constant, it follows that Carolyn's income elasticity of demand is about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.59, and Carolyn regards earrings as an inferior good.",
                        "0.59, and Carolyn regards earrings as a normal good.",
                        "1.7, and Carolyn regards earrings as an inferior good.",
                        "1.7, and Carolyn regards earrings as a normal good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.59, and Carolyn regards earrings as a normal good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 10,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The greater the price elasticity of demand, the",
                    "options": [
                        "more likely the product is a necessity.",
                        "smaller the responsiveness of quantity demanded to a change in price.",
                        "greater the percentage change in price over the percentage change in quantity demanded.",
                        "greater the responsiveness of quantity demanded to a change in price."
                    ],
                    "answer": "greater the responsiveness of quantity demanded to a change in price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 10,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Necessities such as food and clothing tend to have",
                    "options": [
                        "high price elasticities of demand and high income elasticities of demand.",
                        "high price elasticities of demand and low income elasticities of demand.",
                        "low price elasticities of demand and high income elasticities of demand.",
                        "low price elasticities of demand and low income elasticities of demand."
                    ],
                    "answer": "low price elasticities of demand and low income elasticities of demand.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 11,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Whether a good is a luxury or necessity depends on the",
                    "options": [
                        "price of the good.",
                        "preferences of the buyer.",
                        "intrinsic properties of the good.",
                        "scarcity of the good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "preferences of the buyer.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 11,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Income elasticity of demand measures how",
                    "options": [
                        "the quantity demanded changes as consumer income changes.",
                        "consumer purchasing power is affected by a change in the price of a good.",
                        "the price of a good is affected when there is a change in consumer income.",
                        "many units of a good a consumer can buy given a certain income level."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the quantity demanded changes as consumer income changes.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 12,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The price elasticity of demand for bread",
                    "options": [
                        "is computed as the percentage change in quantity demanded of bread divided by the percentage change in price of bread.",
                        "depends, in part, on the availability of close substitutes for bread.",
                        "reflects the many economic, social, and psychological forces that influence consumers' tastes for bread.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 12,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Danita rescues dogs from her local animal shelter. When Danita's income rises by 7 percent, her quantity demanded of dog biscuits increases by 12 percent. For Danita, the income elasticity of demand for dog biscuits is",
                    "options": [
                        "negative, and dog biscuits are a normal good.",
                        "negative, and dog biscuits are an inferior good.",
                        "positive, and dog biscuits are an inferior good.",
                        "positive, and dog biscuits are a normal good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "positive, and dog biscuits are a normal good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 13,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The price elasticity of demand for eggs",
                    "options": [
                        "is computed as the percentage change in quantity demanded of eggs divided by the percentage change in price of eggs.",
                        "will be lower if there is a new invention that is a close substitute for eggs.",
                        "will be higher if consumers consider eggs to be a necessity.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "is computed as the percentage change in quantity demanded of eggs divided by the percentage change in price of eggs.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 13,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For which of the following goods is the income elasticity of demand likely highest?",
                    "options": [
                        "water",
                        "diamonds",
                        "hamburgers",
                        "housing"
                    ],
                    "answer": "diamonds",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 14,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The price elasticity of demand measures the",
                    "options": [
                        "magnitude of the response in quantity demanded to a change in price.",
                        "direction of the shift in the demand curve in response to a market event.",
                        "size of the shortage created by the increase in demand.",
                        "responsiveness of quantity demanded to a change in income."
                    ],
                    "answer": "magnitude of the response in quantity demanded to a change in price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 14,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For which of the following goods is the income elasticity of demand likely highest?",
                    "options": [
                        "natural gas",
                        "doctor's visits",
                        "hamburgers",
                        "boats"
                    ],
                    "answer": "boats",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 15,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price of walnuts rises, many people would switch from consuming walnuts to consuming pecans. But if the price of salt rises, people would have difficulty purchasing something to use in its place. These examples illustrate the importance of",
                    "options": [
                        "the availability of close substitutes in determining the price elasticity of demand.",
                        "a necessity versus a luxury in determining the price elasticity of demand.",
                        "the definition of a market in determining the price elasticity of demand.",
                        "the time horizon in determining the price elasticity of demand."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the availability of close substitutes in determining the price elasticity of demand.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 15,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For which of the following goods is the income elasticity of demand likely lowest?",
                    "options": [
                        "subscriptions to premium movie channels through the local cable television provider",
                        "hi-definition DVD players",
                        "champagne",
                        "housing"
                    ],
                    "answer": "housing",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 16,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that Jane enjoys Diet Coke so much that she consumes one can every day. Although she enjoys gourmet cheese, she consumes it sporadically. If the price of Diet Coke rises, Jane decreases her consumption by only a very small amount. But if the price of gourmet cheese rises, Jane decreases her consumption by a lot. These examples illustrate the importance of",
                    "options": [
                        "the availability of close substitutes in determining the price elasticity of demand.",
                        "a necessity versus a luxury in determining the price elasticity of demand.",
                        "the definition of a market in determining the price elasticity of demand.",
                        "the time horizon in determining the price elasticity of demand."
                    ],
                    "answer": "a necessity versus a luxury in determining the price elasticity of demand.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 16,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For which of the following goods is the income elasticity of demand likely lowest?",
                    "options": [
                        "water",
                        "sapphire pendant necklaces",
                        "filet mignon steaks",
                        "fresh fruit"
                    ],
                    "answer": "water",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 17,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that Juan Carlos is filling out a survey that he received in the mail. The survey asks him what he would do if the price of his favorite toothpaste increased. Juan Carlos reports that he would switch to a different brand. The survey asks what he would do if the price of all toothpastes increased. Juan Carlos reports that he must use toothpaste, so he would have to adjust his spending elsewhere. These examples illustrate the importance of",
                    "options": [
                        "changes in total revenue in determining the price elasticity of demand.",
                        "a necessity versus a luxury in determining the price elasticity of demand.",
                        "the definition of a market in determining the price elasticity of demand.",
                        "the time horizon in determining the price elasticity of demand."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the definition of a market in determining the price elasticity of demand.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 17,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Last year, Joan bought 50 pounds of hamburger when her household's income was $40,000. This year, her household income was only $30,000 and Joan bought 60 pounds of hamburger. All else constant, Joan's income elasticity of demand for hamburger is",
                    "options": [
                        "positive, so Joan considers hamburger to be an inferior good.",
                        "positive, so Joan considers hamburger to be a normal good and a necessity.",
                        "negative, so Joan considers hamburger to be an inferior good.",
                        "negative, so Joan considers hamburger to be a normal good but not a necessity."
                    ],
                    "answer": "negative, so Joan considers hamburger to be an inferior good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 18,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that gasoline prices increase dramatically this month. Lola commutes 100 miles to work each weekday. Over the next few months, Lola drives less on the weekends to try to save money. Within the year, she sells her home and purchases one only 10 miles from her place of employment. These examples illustrate the importance of",
                    "options": [
                        "the availability of substitutes in determining the price elasticity of demand.",
                        "a necessity versus a luxury in determining the price elasticity of demand.",
                        "the definition of a market in determining the price elasticity of demand.",
                        "the time horizon in determining the price elasticity of demand."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the time horizon in determining the price elasticity of demand.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 18,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If an increase in income results in a decrease in the quantity demanded of a good, then for that good, the",
                    "options": [
                        "cross-price elasticity of demand is negative.",
                        "price elasticity of demand is elastic.",
                        "income elasticity of demand is negative.",
                        "income elasticity of demand is positive."
                    ],
                    "answer": "income elasticity of demand is negative.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 19,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Economists compute the price elasticity of demand as the",
                    "options": [
                        "percentage change in price divided by the percentage change in quantity demanded.",
                        "change in quantity demanded divided by the change in the price.",
                        "percentage change in quantity demanded divided by the percentage change in price.",
                        "percentage change in quantity demanded divided by the percentage change in income."
                    ],
                    "answer": "percentage change in quantity demanded divided by the percentage change in price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 19,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "To determine whether a good is considered normal or inferior, one could examine the value of the",
                    "options": [
                        "income elasticity of demand for that good.",
                        "price elasticity of demand for that good.",
                        "price elasticity of supply for that good.",
                        "cross-price elasticity of demand for that good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "income elasticity of demand for that good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 20,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-1. Which of the following is consistent with the elasticities given in Table 5-2?",
                    "options": [
                        "A is a luxury, and B is a necessity.",
                        "A is a good several years after a price increase, and B is that same good several days after the price increase.",
                        "A is a Kit Kat bar, and B is candy.",
                        "A has fewer substitutes than B."
                    ],
                    "answer": "A has fewer substitutes than B.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 20,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You and your college roommate eat three packages of Ramen noodles each week. After graduation last month, both of you were hired at several times your college income. You still enjoy Ramen noodles very much and buy even more, but your roommate plans to buy fewer Ramen noodles in favor of foods she prefers more. When looking at income elasticity of demand for Ramen noodles, yours would",
                    "options": [
                        "be negative, and your roommate's would be positive.",
                        "be positive, and your roommate's would be negative.",
                        "be zero, and your roommate's would approach infinity.",
                        "approach infinity, and your roommate's would be zero."
                    ],
                    "answer": "be positive, and your roommate's would be negative.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 21,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-1. Which of the following is consistent with the elasticities given in Table 5-2?",
                    "options": [
                        "A is grapes, and B is fruit.",
                        "A is T-shirts, and B is socks.",
                        "A is train tickets before cars were invented, and B is train tickets after cars were invented.",
                        "A is diamond necklaces, and B is beds."
                    ],
                    "answer": "A is train tickets before cars were invented, and B is train tickets after cars were invented.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 21,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You and your college roommate eat three packages of Ramen noodles each week. After graduation last month, both of you were hired at several times your college income. Your roommate still enjoys Ramen noodles very much and buys even more, but you plan to buy fewer Ramen noodles in favor of foods you prefer more. When looking at income elasticity of demand for Ramen noodles, yours would",
                    "options": [
                        "be negative and your roommate's would be positive.",
                        "be positive and your roommate's would be negative.",
                        "be zero and your roommate's would approach infinity.",
                        "approach infinity and your roommate's would be zero."
                    ],
                    "answer": "be negative and your roommate's would be positive.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 22,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-1. Which of the following is consistent with the elasticities given in Table 5-2?",
                    "options": [
                        "A is root beer, and B is carbonated beverages.",
                        "A is bicycles, and B is mopeds.",
                        "A is airline tickets in the short run, and B is airline tickets in the long run.",
                        "A is gourmet coffee, and B is dentist's visits."
                    ],
                    "answer": "A is airline tickets in the short run, and B is airline tickets in the long run.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 22,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose good X has a negative income elasticity of demand. This implies that good X is",
                    "options": [
                        "a normal good.",
                        "a necessity.",
                        "an inferior good.",
                        "a luxury."
                    ],
                    "answer": "an inferior good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 23,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose there is a 6 percent increase in the price of good X and a resulting 6 percent decrease in the quantity of X demanded. Price elasticity of demand for X is",
                    "options": [
                        "0.",
                        "1.",
                        "6.",
                        "36."
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 23,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose good X has a positive income elasticity of demand. This implies that good X could be (i) a normal good. (ii) a necessity. (iii) an inferior good. (iv) a luxury.",
                    "options": [
                        "(i) only",
                        "(i) and (ii) only",
                        "(i), (ii), and (iv) only",
                        "(iii) only"
                    ],
                    "answer": "(i), (ii), and (iv) only",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 24,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price elasticity of demand for a good is 4.0, then a 10 percent increase in price results in a",
                    "options": [
                        "0.4 percent decrease in the quantity demanded.",
                        "2.5 percent decrease in the quantity demanded.",
                        "4 percent decrease in the quantity demanded.",
                        "40 percent decrease in the quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "40 percent decrease in the quantity demanded.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 24,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For which of the following types of goods would the income elasticity of demand be positive and relatively large?",
                    "options": [
                        "all inferior goods",
                        "all normal goods",
                        "goods for which there are many complements",
                        "luxuries"
                    ],
                    "answer": "luxuries",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 25,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price elasticity of demand for a good is 10.0, then a 4 percent increase in price results in a",
                    "options": [
                        "0.4 percent decrease in the quantity demanded.",
                        "2.5 percent decrease in the quantity demanded.",
                        "4 percent decrease in the quantity demanded.",
                        "40 percent decrease in the quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "40 percent decrease in the quantity demanded.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 25,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Assume that a 4 percent increase in income results in a 2 percent increase in the quantity demanded of a good. The income elasticity of demand for the good is",
                    "options": [
                        "negative, and the good is an inferior good.",
                        "negative, and the good is a normal good.",
                        "positive, and the good is a normal good.",
                        "positive, and the good is an inferior good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "positive, and the good is a normal good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 26,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price elasticity of demand for a good is 0.4, then a 10 percent increase in price results in a",
                    "options": [
                        "0.4 percent decrease in the quantity demanded.",
                        "2.5 percent decrease in the quantity demanded.",
                        "4 percent decrease in the quantity demanded.",
                        "40 percent decrease in the quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "4 percent decrease in the quantity demanded.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 26,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Assume that a 4 percent decrease in income results in a 6 percent increase in the quantity demanded of a good. The income elasticity of demand for the good is",
                    "options": [
                        "negative, and the good is an inferior good.",
                        "negative, and the good is a normal good.",
                        "positive, and the good is an inferior good.",
                        "positive, and the good is a normal good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "negative, and the good is an inferior good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 27,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price elasticity of demand for a good is 0.25, then a 20 percent decrease in price results in a",
                    "options": [
                        "0.0125 percent increase in the quantity demanded.",
                        "4 percent increase in the quantity demanded.",
                        "5 percent increase in the quantity demanded.",
                        "80 percent increase in the quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "5 percent increase in the quantity demanded.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 27,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Reta's income elasticity of demand for steak dinners is 1.50. All else equal, this means that if her income increases by 20 percent, she will buy",
                    "options": [
                        "150 percent more steak dinners.",
                        "50 percent more steak dinners.",
                        "30 percent more steak dinners.",
                        "20 percent more steak dinners."
                    ],
                    "answer": "30 percent more steak dinners.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 28,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price elasticity of demand for a good is 1.5, then a 3 percent decrease in price results in a",
                    "options": [
                        "0.5 percent increase in the quantity demanded.",
                        "2 percent increase in the quantity demanded.",
                        "4.5 percent increase in the quantity demanded.",
                        "5 percent increase in the quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "4.5 percent increase in the quantity demanded.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 28,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When her income increased from $10,000 to $20,000, Heather's consumption of macaroni decreased from 10 pounds to 5 pounds and her consumption of soy-burgers increased from 2 pounds to 4 pounds. We can conclude that for Heather, macaroni",
                    "options": [
                        "and soy-burgers are both normal goods with income elasticities equal to 1.",
                        "is an inferior good and soy-burgers are normal goods; both have income elasticities of 1.",
                        "is an inferior good with an income elasticity of -1 and soy-burgers are normal goods with an income elasticity of 1.",
                        "and soy-burgers are both inferior goods with income elasticities equal to -1."
                    ],
                    "answer": "is an inferior good with an income elasticity of -1 and soy-burgers are normal goods with an income elasticity of 1.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 29,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price elasticity of demand for a good is 0.2, then a 3 percent decrease in price results in a",
                    "options": [
                        "0.6 percent increase in the quantity demanded.",
                        "1.5 percent increase in the quantity demanded.",
                        "2 percent increase in the quantity demanded.",
                        "6 percent increase in the quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.6 percent increase in the quantity demanded.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 29,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following should be held constant when calculating an income elasticity of demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "the quantity of the good demanded",
                        "the price of the good",
                        "income",
                        "All of the above should be held constant."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the price of the good",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 30,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price elasticity of demand for a good is 1, then a 3 percent decrease in price results in a",
                    "options": [
                        "0.1 percent increase in the quantity demanded.",
                        "1 percent increase in the quantity demanded.",
                        "3 percent increase in the quantity demanded.",
                        "4 percent increase in the quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "3 percent increase in the quantity demanded.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 30,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following should be held constant when calculating an income elasticity of demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "the price of the good",
                        "prices of related goods",
                        "tastes",
                        "All of the above should be held constant."
                    ],
                    "answer": "All of the above should be held constant.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 31,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price elasticity of demand for a good is 4, then a 12 percent decrease in price results in a",
                    "options": [
                        "0.33 percent increase in the quantity demanded.",
                        "3 percent increase in the quantity demanded.",
                        "30 percent increase in the quantity demanded.",
                        "48 percent increase in the quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "48 percent increase in the quantity demanded.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 31,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Food and clothing tend to have",
                    "options": [
                        "small income elasticities because consumers, regardless of their incomes, choose to buy relatively constant quantities of these goods.",
                        "small income elasticities because consumers buy proportionately more of both goods at higher income levels than they buy at low income levels.",
                        "large income elasticities because they are necessities.",
                        "large income elasticities because they are relatively inexpensive."
                    ],
                    "answer": "small income elasticities because consumers, regardless of their incomes, choose to buy relatively constant quantities of these goods.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 32,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price elasticity of demand for a good is 0.8, then which of the following events is consistent with a 4 percent decrease in the quantity of the good demanded?",
                    "options": [
                        "a 0.2 percent increase in the price of the good",
                        "a 3.2 percent increase in the price of the good",
                        "a 4.8 percent increase in the price of the good",
                        "a 5 percent increase in the price of the good"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a 5 percent increase in the price of the good",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 32,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The income elasticity of demand for caviar tends to be",
                    "options": [
                        "high because caviar is relatively expensive.",
                        "low because caviar is packaged in small containers.",
                        "high because buyers generally feel that they can do without it.",
                        "low because it is almost always in short supply."
                    ],
                    "answer": "high because buyers generally feel that they can do without it.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 33,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For a particular good, a 2 percent increase in price causes a 12 percent decrease in quantity demanded. Which of the following statements is most likely applicable to this good?",
                    "options": [
                        "There are no close substitutes for this good.",
                        "The good is a luxury.",
                        "The market for the good is broadly defined.",
                        "The relevant time horizon is short."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The good is a luxury.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 33,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "While in college, John and Bethany each buy five packages of mac-n-cheese per week. After they graduate and have full-time jobs, John buys six packages per week, but Bethany buys only two packages per week. When looking at income elasticity of demand for mac-n-cheese, John's",
                    "options": [
                        "is negative, and Bethany's is positive.",
                        "is positive, and Bethany's is negative.",
                        "is zero, and Bethany's approaches infinity.",
                        "approaches infinity, and Bethany's is zero."
                    ],
                    "answer": "is positive, and Bethany's is negative.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 34,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For a particular good, a 5 percent increase in price causes a 15 percent decrease in quantity demanded. Which of the following statements is most likely applicable to this good?",
                    "options": [
                        "There are many substitutes for this good.",
                        "The good is a necessity.",
                        "The market for the good is broadly defined.",
                        "The relevant time horizon is short."
                    ],
                    "answer": "There are many substitutes for this good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 34,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Charles purchases 20 basketball tickets per year when his annual income is $50,000 and 25 basketball tickets when his annual income is $60,000. Charles's income elasticity of demand for basketball ticket is",
                    "options": [
                        "0.82, and basketball tickets are a normal good.",
                        "0.82, and basketball tickets are an inferior good.",
                        "1.22, and basketball tickets are a normal good.",
                        "1.22, and basketball tickets are an inferior good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.22, and basketball tickets are a normal good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 35,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For a particular good, a 10 percent increase in price causes a 5 percent decrease in quantity demanded. Which of the following statements is most likely applicable to this good?",
                    "options": [
                        "There are many close substitutes for this good.",
                        "The good is a necessity.",
                        "The market for the good is narrowly defined.",
                        "The relevant time horizon is long."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The good is a necessity.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 35,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Tyler purchases 5 pounds of hot dogs per month when his monthly income is $2,000 and 4 pounds of hot dogs per month when his monthly income is $2,200. Tyler's income elasticity of demand for hot dogs is",
                    "options": [
                        "2.33, and hot dogs are a normal good.",
                        "-2.33, and hot dogs are an inferior good.",
                        "0.43, and hot dogs are a normal good.",
                        "-0.43, and hot dogs are an inferior good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "-2.33, and hot dogs are an inferior good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 36,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For a particular good, a 10 percent increase in price causes a 15 percent decrease in quantity demanded. Which of the following statements is most likely applicable to this good?",
                    "options": [
                        "There are no close substitutes for this good.",
                        "The good is a necessity.",
                        "The market for the good is broadly defined.",
                        "The relevant time horizon is long."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The relevant time horizon is long.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 36,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose goods A and B are substitutes for each other. We would expect the cross-price elasticity between these two goods to be",
                    "options": [
                        "positive.",
                        "negative.",
                        "either positive or negative. It depends whether A and B are normal goods or inferior goods.",
                        "either positive or negative. It depends whether the current price level is on the elastic or inelastic portion of the demand curve."
                    ],
                    "answer": "positive.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 37,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For a particular good, a 5 percent increase in price causes a 2 percent decrease in quantity demanded. Which of the following statements is most likely applicable to this good?",
                    "options": [
                        "There are many close substitutes for this good.",
                        "The good is a luxury.",
                        "The market for the good is broadly defined.",
                        "The relevant time horizon is long."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The market for the good is broadly defined.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 37,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Last month, sellers of good Y took in $100 in total revenue on sales of 50 units of good Y. This month sellers of good Y raised their price and took in $120 in total revenue on sales of 40 units of good Y. At the same time, the price of good X stayed the same, but sales of good X increased from 20 units to 40 units. We can conclude that goods X and Y are",
                    "options": [
                        "substitutes, and have a cross-price elasticity of 0.60.",
                        "complements, and have a cross-price elasticity of 0.60.",
                        "substitutes, and have a cross-price elasticity of 1.67.",
                        "complements, and have a cross-price elasticity of 1.67."
                    ],
                    "answer": "substitutes, and have a cross-price elasticity of 1.67.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 38,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For a particular good, a 12 percent increase in price causes a 3 percent decrease in quantity demanded. Which of the following statements is most likely applicable to this good?",
                    "options": [
                        "There are many substitutes for this good.",
                        "The good is a necessity.",
                        "The market for the good is narrowly defined.",
                        "The relevant time horizon is long."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The good is a necessity.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 38,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following could be the cross-price elasticity of demand for two goods that are complements?",
                    "options": [
                        "-1.3",
                        "0",
                        "0.2",
                        "1.4"
                    ],
                    "answer": "-1.3",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 39,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For a particular good, a 3 percent increase in price causes a 10 percent decrease in quantity demanded. Which of the following statements is most likely applicable to this good?",
                    "options": [
                        "The relevant time horizon is short.",
                        "The good is a necessity.",
                        "The market for the good is broadly defined.",
                        "There are many close substitutes for this good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "There are many close substitutes for this good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 39,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that when the price of good X falls from $10 to $8, the quantity demanded of good Y rises from 20 units to 25 units. Using the midpoint method, the cross-price elasticity of demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "-1.0, and X and Y are complements.",
                        "-1.0, and X and Y are substitutes.",
                        "1.0, and X and Y are complements.",
                        "1.0, and X and Y are substitutes."
                    ],
                    "answer": "-1.0, and X and Y are complements.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 40,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For a particular good, a 10 percent increase in price causes a 3 percent decrease in quantity demanded. Which of the following statements is most likely applicable to this good?",
                    "options": [
                        "The relevant time horizon is short.",
                        "The good is a luxury.",
                        "The market for the good is narrowly defined.",
                        "There are many close substitutes for this good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The relevant time horizon is short.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 40,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following expressions represents a cross-price elasticity of demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "percentage change in quantity demanded of bread divided by percentage change in quantity supplied of bread",
                        "percentage change in quantity demanded of bread divided by percentage change in price of butter",
                        "percentage change in price of bread divided by percentage change in quantity demanded of bread",
                        "percentage change in quantity demanded of bread divided by percentage change in income"
                    ],
                    "answer": "percentage change in quantity demanded of bread divided by percentage change in price of butter",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 41,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price elasticity of demand for a good is 6, then a 3 percent decrease in price results in",
                    "options": [
                        "a 20 percent increase in the quantity demanded.",
                        "an 18 percent increase in the quantity demanded.",
                        "a 2 percent increase in the quantity demanded.",
                        "a 1.8 percent increase in the quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "an 18 percent increase in the quantity demanded.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 41,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Cross-price elasticity of demand measures how",
                    "options": [
                        "the price of one good changes in response to a change in the price of another good.",
                        "the quantity demanded of one good changes in response to a change in the quantity demanded of another good.",
                        "the quantity demanded of one good changes in response to a change in the price of another good.",
                        "strongly normal or inferior a good is."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the quantity demanded of one good changes in response to a change in the price of another good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 42,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Elasticity of demand is closely related to the slope of the demand curve. The more responsive buyers are to a change in price, the",
                    "options": [
                        "steeper the demand curve will be.",
                        "flatter the demand curve will be.",
                        "further to the right the demand curve will sit.",
                        "closer to the vertical axis the demand curve will sit."
                    ],
                    "answer": "flatter the demand curve will be.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 42,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The cross-price elasticity of demand can tell us whether goods are",
                    "options": [
                        "normal or inferior.",
                        "elastic or inelastic.",
                        "luxuries or necessities.",
                        "complements or substitutes."
                    ],
                    "answer": "complements or substitutes.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 43,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Elasticity of demand is closely related to the slope of the demand curve. The less responsive buyers are to a change in price, the",
                    "options": [
                        "steeper the demand curve will be.",
                        "flatter the demand curve will be.",
                        "further to the right the demand curve will sit.",
                        "closer to the vertical axis the demand curve will sit."
                    ],
                    "answer": "steeper the demand curve will be.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 43,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the cross-price elasticity of two goods is negative, then the two goods are",
                    "options": [
                        "necessities.",
                        "complements.",
                        "normal goods.",
                        "inferior goods."
                    ],
                    "answer": "complements.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 44,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The flatter the demand curve through a given point, the",
                    "options": [
                        "greater the price elasticity of demand at that point.",
                        "smaller the price elasticity of demand at that point.",
                        "closer the price elasticity of demand will be to the slope of the curve.",
                        "greater the absolute value of the change in total revenue when there is a movement from that point upward and to the left along the demand curve."
                    ],
                    "answer": "greater the price elasticity of demand at that point.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 44,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the cross-price elasticity of two goods is positive, then the two goods are",
                    "options": [
                        "substitutes.",
                        "complements.",
                        "normal goods.",
                        "inferior goods."
                    ],
                    "answer": "substitutes.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 45,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The smaller the price elasticity of demand, the",
                    "options": [
                        "steeper the demand curve will be through a given point.",
                        "flatter the demand curve will be through a given point.",
                        "more strongly buyers respond to a change in price between any two prices P1 and P2.",
                        "smaller the decrease in equilibrium price when the supply curve shifts rightward from S1 to S2."
                    ],
                    "answer": "steeper the demand curve will be through a given point.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 45,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose the cross-price elasticity of demand between hot dogs and mustard is -2.00. This implies that a 20 percent increase in the price of hot dogs will cause the quantity of mustard purchased to",
                    "options": [
                        "fall by 200 percent.",
                        "fall by 40 percent.",
                        "rise by 200 percent.",
                        "rise by 40 percent."
                    ],
                    "answer": "fall by 40 percent.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 46,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "As we move downward and to the right along a linear, downward-sloping demand curve,",
                    "options": [
                        "both slope and elasticity remain constant.",
                        "slope changes but elasticity remains constant.",
                        "both slope and elasticity change.",
                        "slope remains constant but elasticity changes."
                    ],
                    "answer": "slope remains constant but elasticity changes.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 46,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If two goods are substitutes, their cross-price elasticity will be",
                    "options": [
                        "positive.",
                        "negative.",
                        "zero.",
                        "equal to the difference between the income elasticities of demand for the two goods."
                    ],
                    "answer": "positive.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 47,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The difference between slope and elasticity is that slope",
                    "options": [
                        "is a ratio of two changes, and elasticity is a ratio of two percentage changes.",
                        "is a ratio of two percentage changes, and elasticity is a ratio of two changes.",
                        "measures changes in quantity demanded more accurately than elasticity.",
                        "none of the above; there is no difference between slope and elasticity."
                    ],
                    "answer": "is a ratio of two changes, and elasticity is a ratio of two percentage changes.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 47,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If two goods are complements, their cross-price elasticity will be",
                    "options": [
                        "positive.",
                        "negative.",
                        "zero.",
                        "equal to the difference between the income elasticities of demand for the two goods."
                    ],
                    "answer": "negative.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 48,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Goods with many close substitutes tend to have",
                    "options": [
                        "more elastic demands.",
                        "less elastic demands.",
                        "price elasticities of demand that are unit elastic.",
                        "income elasticities of demand that are negative."
                    ],
                    "answer": "more elastic demands.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 48,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For which pairs of goods is the cross-price elasticity most likely to be positive?",
                    "options": [
                        "peanut butter and jelly",
                        "bicycle frames and bicycle tires",
                        "pens and pencils",
                        "college textbooks and iPods"
                    ],
                    "answer": "pens and pencils",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 49,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For a good that is a luxury, demand",
                    "options": [
                        "tends to be inelastic.",
                        "tends to be elastic.",
                        "has unit elasticity.",
                        "cannot be represented by a demand curve in the usual way."
                    ],
                    "answer": "tends to be elastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 49,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For which pairs of goods is the cross-price elasticity most likely to be negative?",
                    "options": [
                        "peanut butter and jelly",
                        "automobile tires and coffee",
                        "pens and pencils",
                        "paperback novels and electronic books for e-readers"
                    ],
                    "answer": "peanut butter and jelly",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 50,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The demand for Godiva pumpkin truffles is likely quite elastic because",
                    "options": [
                        "truffles melt easily.",
                        "this particular type of chocolate is viewed as a necessity by many chocolate lovers.",
                        "the market is broadly defined.",
                        "other types of chocolate are good substitutes for this particular flavor."
                    ],
                    "answer": "other types of chocolate are good substitutes for this particular flavor.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 50,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the cross-price elasticity of demand for two goods is 1.25, then",
                    "options": [
                        "the two goods are luxuries.",
                        "the two goods are substitutes.",
                        "one of the goods is normal and the other good is inferior.",
                        "the demand for one of the goods conforms to the law of demand, but the demand for the other good violates the law of demand."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the two goods are substitutes.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 51,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The demand for Hubba Bubba bubble gum is likely",
                    "options": [
                        "elastic because gum is expensive relative to other snacks.",
                        "elastic because there are many close substitutes for Hubba Bubba.",
                        "elastic because bubble gum is regarded as a necessity by many people.",
                        "inelastic because it is consumed quickly, making the relevant time horizon short."
                    ],
                    "answer": "elastic because there are many close substitutes for Hubba Bubba.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 51,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the cross-price elasticity of demand for two goods is -4.5, then",
                    "options": [
                        "the two goods are substitutes.",
                        "the two goods are complements.",
                        "one of the goods is normal while the other good is inferior.",
                        "one of the goods is a luxury while the other good is a necessity."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the two goods are complements.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 52,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A good will have a more elastic demand, the",
                    "options": [
                        "greater the availability of close substitutes.",
                        "more broad the definition of the market.",
                        "shorter the period of time.",
                        "more it is regarded as a necessity."
                    ],
                    "answer": "greater the availability of close substitutes.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 52,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Sandra purchases 5 pounds of coffee and 10 gallons of milk per month when the price of coffee is $10 per pound. She purchases 6 pounds of coffee and 12 gallons of milk per month when the price of coffee is $8 per pound. Sandra's cross-price elasticity of demand for coffee and milk is",
                    "options": [
                        "0.82, and they are substitutes.",
                        "-0.82, and they are complements.",
                        "1.22, and they are substitutes.",
                        "-1.22, and they are complements."
                    ],
                    "answer": "-0.82, and they are complements.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 53,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "The demand for flat-screen computer monitors is more elastic than the demand for monitors in general.",
                        "The demand for grandfather clocks is more elastic than the demand for clocks in general.",
                        "The demand for cardboard is more elastic over a long period of time than over a short period of time.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 54,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "The demand for natural gas is more elastic over a short period of time than over a long period of time.",
                        "The demand for smoke alarms is more elastic than the demand for Persian rugs.",
                        "The demand for bourbon whiskey is more elastic than the demand for alcoholic beverages in general.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The demand for bourbon whiskey is more elastic than the demand for alcoholic beverages in general.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 55,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The value of the price elasticity of demand for a good will be relatively large when",
                    "options": [
                        "there are no good substitutes available for the good.",
                        "the time period in question is relatively short.",
                        "the good is a luxury rather than a necessity.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the good is a luxury rather than a necessity.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 56,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price elasticity of demand is 1.5, regardless of which two points on the demand curve are used to compute the elasticity, then demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "perfectly inelastic, and the demand curve is vertical.",
                        "elastic, and the demand curve is a straight, downward-sloping line.",
                        "perfectly elastic, and the demand curve is horizontal.",
                        "elastic, and the demand curve is something other than a straight, downward-sloping line."
                    ],
                    "answer": "elastic, and the demand curve is something other than a straight, downward-sloping line.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 57,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that quantity demand falls by 30% as a result of a 5% increase in price. The price elasticity of demand for this good is",
                    "options": [
                        "inelastic and equal to 6.",
                        "elastic and equal to 6.",
                        "inelastic and equal to 0.17.",
                        "elastic and equal to 0.17."
                    ],
                    "answer": "elastic and equal to 6.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 58,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is likely to have the most price elastic demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "clothing",
                        "blue jeans",
                        "Tommy Hilfiger jeans",
                        "All three would have the same elasticity of demand because they are all related."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Tommy Hilfiger jeans",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 59,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is likely to have the most price elastic demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "ice cream",
                        "frozen yogurt",
                        "vanilla ice cream",
                        "Häagen-Dazs(R) vanilla bean ice cream"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Häagen-Dazs(R) vanilla bean ice cream",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 60,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is likely to have the most price elastic demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "lattés",
                        "doctor's visits",
                        "eggs",
                        "natural gas"
                    ],
                    "answer": "lattés",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 61,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is likely to have the most price elastic demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "dental floss",
                        "milk",
                        "salt",
                        "diamond earrings"
                    ],
                    "answer": "diamond earrings",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 62,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is likely to have the most price elastic demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "gasoline in the short run",
                        "dentist's visits",
                        "ice cream",
                        "deodorant"
                    ],
                    "answer": "ice cream",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 63,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Demand is said to be price elastic if",
                    "options": [
                        "the price of the good responds substantially to changes in demand.",
                        "demand shifts substantially when income or the expected future price of the good changes.",
                        "buyers do not respond much to changes in the price of the good.",
                        "buyers respond substantially to changes in the price of the good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "buyers respond substantially to changes in the price of the good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 64,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When quantity demanded responds strongly to changes in price, demand is said to be",
                    "options": [
                        "fluid.",
                        "elastic.",
                        "dynamic.",
                        "highly variable."
                    ],
                    "answer": "elastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 65,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Demand is elastic if the price elasticity of demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "less than 1.",
                        "equal to 1.",
                        "equal to 0.",
                        "greater than 1."
                    ],
                    "answer": "greater than 1.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 66,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For a good that is a necessity,",
                    "options": [
                        "quantity demanded tends to respond substantially to a change in price.",
                        "demand tends to be inelastic.",
                        "the law of demand does not apply.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "demand tends to be inelastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 67,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is likely to have the most price inelastic demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "mint-flavored toothpaste",
                        "toothpaste",
                        "Colgate mint-flavored toothpaste",
                        "a generic mint-flavored toothpaste"
                    ],
                    "answer": "toothpaste",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 68,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is likely to have the most price inelastic demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "white chocolate chip with macadamia nut cookies",
                        "Mrs. Field's chocolate chip cookies",
                        "milk chocolate chip cookies",
                        "cookies"
                    ],
                    "answer": "cookies",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 69,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is likely to have the most price inelastic demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "white chocolate chip with macadamia nut cookies",
                        "hardback novels",
                        "salt",
                        "box seats at a major league baseball game"
                    ],
                    "answer": "salt",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 70,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is likely to have the most price inelastic demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "laptop computers",
                        "iPod shuffles",
                        "designer jeans",
                        "college tuition for a junior or senior"
                    ],
                    "answer": "college tuition for a junior or senior",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 71,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is likely to have the most price inelastic demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "strawberry-banana milk shakes",
                        "gasoline in the short run",
                        "diamond earrings",
                        "box seats at a major league baseball game"
                    ],
                    "answer": "gasoline in the short run",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 72,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is likely to have the most price inelastic demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "chocolate",
                        "Godiva chocolate",
                        "Hershey's chocolate",
                        "All three would have the same elasticity of demand because they are all related."
                    ],
                    "answer": "chocolate",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 73,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is likely to have the most price inelastic demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "camcorders",
                        "insulin",
                        "apples",
                        "devices that remove cores from apples"
                    ],
                    "answer": "insulin",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 74,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is likely to have the most price inelastic demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "athletic shoes",
                        "running shoes",
                        "Nike running shoes",
                        "Nike Shox running shoes"
                    ],
                    "answer": "athletic shoes",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 75,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is likely to have the most price inelastic demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "lattés",
                        "filet mignon",
                        "Grey Goose(R) vodka",
                        "milk"
                    ],
                    "answer": "milk",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 76,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For a good that is a necessity, demand",
                    "options": [
                        "tends to be inelastic.",
                        "tends to be elastic.",
                        "has unit elasticity.",
                        "cannot be represented by a demand curve in the usual way."
                    ],
                    "answer": "tends to be inelastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 77,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A person who takes a prescription drug to control high cholesterol most likely has a demand for that drug that is",
                    "options": [
                        "inelastic.",
                        "unit elastic.",
                        "elastic.",
                        "highly responsive to changes in income."
                    ],
                    "answer": "inelastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 78,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "There are very few, if any, good substitutes for motor oil. Therefore, the",
                    "options": [
                        "demand for motor oil would tend to be inelastic.",
                        "demand for motor oil would tend to be elastic.",
                        "demand for motor oil would tend to respond strongly to changes in prices of other goods.",
                        "supply of motor oil would tend to respond strongly to changes in people's tastes for large cars relative to their tastes for small cars."
                    ],
                    "answer": "demand for motor oil would tend to be inelastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 79,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A good will have a more inelastic demand, the",
                    "options": [
                        "greater the availability of close substitutes.",
                        "broader the definition of the market.",
                        "longer the period of time.",
                        "more it is regarded as a luxury."
                    ],
                    "answer": "broader the definition of the market.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 80,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Other things equal, the demand for a good tends to be more inelastic, the",
                    "options": [
                        "fewer the available substitutes.",
                        "longer the time period considered.",
                        "more the good is considered a luxury good.",
                        "more narrowly defined is the market for the good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "fewer the available substitutes.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 81,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that quantity demand rises by 10% as a result of a 15% decrease in price. The price elasticity of demand for this good is",
                    "options": [
                        "inelastic and equal to 0.67.",
                        "elastic and equal to 0.67.",
                        "inelastic and equal to 1.50.",
                        "elastic and equal to 1.50."
                    ],
                    "answer": "inelastic and equal to 0.67.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 82,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "There are very few, if any, good substitutes for automotive tires. Therefore, the demand for automotive tires would tend to be",
                    "options": [
                        "elastic.",
                        "unit elastic.",
                        "inelastic.",
                        "highly responsive to changes in income as well as changes in prices."
                    ],
                    "answer": "inelastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 83,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Demand is said to be inelastic if",
                    "options": [
                        "buyers respond substantially to changes in the price of the good.",
                        "demand shifts only slightly when the price of the good changes.",
                        "the quantity demanded changes only slightly when the price of the good changes.",
                        "the price of the good responds only slightly to changes in demand."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the quantity demanded changes only slightly when the price of the good changes.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 84,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If demand is price inelastic, then",
                    "options": [
                        "buyers do not respond much to a change in price.",
                        "buyers respond substantially to a change in price, but the response is very slow.",
                        "buyers do not alter their quantities demanded much in response to advertising, fads, or general changes in tastes.",
                        "the demand curve is very flat."
                    ],
                    "answer": "buyers do not respond much to a change in price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 85,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the quantity demanded of a certain good responds only slightly to a change in the price of the good, then the",
                    "options": [
                        "demand for the good is said to be elastic.",
                        "demand for the good is said to be inelastic.",
                        "law of demand does not apply to the good.",
                        "demand curve for the good shifts only slightly in response to a change in price."
                    ],
                    "answer": "demand for the good is said to be inelastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 86,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Demand is inelastic if the price elasticity of demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "less than 1.",
                        "equal to 1.",
                        "greater than 1.",
                        "equal to 0."
                    ],
                    "answer": "less than 1.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 87,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Demand is said to be inelastic if the",
                    "options": [
                        "quantity demanded changes proportionately more than price.",
                        "price changes proportionately more than income.",
                        "quantity demanded changes proportionately less than price.",
                        "quantity demanded changes proportionately the same as price."
                    ],
                    "answer": "quantity demanded changes proportionately less than price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 88,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When the price of bubble gum is $0.50, the quantity demanded is 400 packs per day. When the price falls to $0.40, the quantity demanded increases to 600. Given this information and using the midpoint method, we know that the demand for bubble gum is",
                    "options": [
                        "inelastic.",
                        "elastic.",
                        "unit elastic.",
                        "perfectly inelastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "elastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 89,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The midpoint method is used to compute elasticity because it",
                    "options": [
                        "automatically computes a positive number instead of a negative number.",
                        "results in an elasticity that is the same as the slope of the demand curve.",
                        "gives the same answer regardless of the direction of change.",
                        "automatically rounds quantities to the nearest whole unit."
                    ],
                    "answer": "gives the same answer regardless of the direction of change.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 90,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose the price of potato chips decreases from $1.45 to $1.25 and, as a result, the quantity of potato chips demanded increases from 2,000 to 2,200. Using the midpoint method, the price elasticity of demand for potato chips in the given price range is",
                    "options": [
                        "2.00.",
                        "1.55.",
                        "1.00.",
                        "0.64."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.64.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 91,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Using the midpoint method, the price elasticity of demand for a good is computed to be approximately 0.75. Which of the following events is consistent with a 10 percent decrease in the quantity of the good demanded?",
                    "options": [
                        "a 7.5 increase in the price of the good",
                        "a 13.33 percent increase in the price of the good",
                        "an increase in the price of the good from $7.50 to $10",
                        "an increase in the price of the good from $10 to $17.50"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a 13.33 percent increase in the price of the good",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 92,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Using the midpoint method, the price elasticity of demand for a good is computed to be approximately 2. Which of the following events is consistent with a 0.1 percent increase in the price of the good?",
                    "options": [
                        "The quantity of the good demanded decreases from 250 to 150.",
                        "The quantity of the good demanded decreases from 200 to 100.",
                        "The quantity of the good demanded decreases by 0.05 percent.",
                        "The quantity of the good demanded decreases by 0.2 percent."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The quantity of the good demanded decreases by 0.2 percent.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 93,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Studies indicate that the price elasticity of demand for cigarettes is about 0.4. A government policy aimed at reducing smoking changed the price of a pack of cigarettes from $2 to $6. According to the midpoint method, the government policy should have reduced smoking by",
                    "options": [
                        "30%.",
                        "40%.",
                        "80%.",
                        "250%."
                    ],
                    "answer": "40%.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 94,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When the price of a good is $5, the quantity demanded is 100 units per month; when the price is $7, the quantity demanded is 80 units per month. Using the midpoint method, the price elasticity of demand is about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.22.",
                        "0.67.",
                        "1.33.",
                        "1.50."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.67.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 95,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When the price of a good is $5, the quantity demanded is 120 units per month; when the price is $7, the quantity demanded is 100 units per month. Using the midpoint method, the price elasticity of demand is about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.55.",
                        "1.83.",
                        "2.",
                        "10."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.55.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 96,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When the price of a bracelet was $25 each, the jewelry shop sold 20 per month. When it raised the price to $35 each, it sold 14 per month. Using the midpoint method, the price elasticity of demand for bracelets is about",
                    "options": [
                        "1.66.",
                        "1.06.",
                        "0.94.",
                        "0.60."
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.06.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 97,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following expressions is valid for the price elasticity of demand? . Price elasticity of demand = . Price elasticity of demand = .",
                    "options": [
                        "Price elasticity of demand = .",
                        "Price elasticity of demand =",
                        "",
                        ""
                    ],
                    "answer": "Price elasticity of demand =",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 98,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following expressions can be used to compute the price elasticity of demand? • Price elasticity of demand = . Price elasticity of demand = • . Price elasticity of demand = • .",
                    "options": [
                        "Price elasticity of demand = • .",
                        "",
                        "",
                        ""
                    ],
                    "answer": "C",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 99,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that 50 ice cream cones are demanded at a particular price. If the price of ice cream cones rises from that price by 4 percent, the number of ice cream cones demanded falls to 46. Using the midpoint approach to calculate the price elasticity of demand, it follows that the",
                    "options": [
                        "demand for ice cream cones in this price range is elastic.",
                        "demand for ice cream cones in this price range is inelastic.",
                        "demand for ice cream cones in this price range is unit elastic.",
                        "price elasticity of demand for ice cream cones in this price range is 0."
                    ],
                    "answer": "demand for ice cream cones in this price range is elastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 100,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When the price of used cds is $4, Daphne buys five per month. When the price is $3, she buys nine per month. Daphne's demand for used cds is",
                    "options": [
                        "elastic, and her demand curve would be relatively flat.",
                        "elastic, and her demand curve would be relatively steep.",
                        "inelastic, and her demand curve would be relatively flat.",
                        "inelastic, and her demand curve would be relatively steep."
                    ],
                    "answer": "elastic, and her demand curve would be relatively flat.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 101,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The midpoint method for calculating elasticities is convenient in that it allows us to",
                    "options": [
                        "ignore the percentage change in quantity demanded and instead focus entirely on the percentage change in price.",
                        "calculate the same value for the elasticity, regardless of whether the price increases or decreases.",
                        "assume that sellers' total revenue stays constant when the price changes.",
                        "restrict all elasticity values to between 0 and 1."
                    ],
                    "answer": "calculate the same value for the elasticity, regardless of whether the price increases or decreases.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 102,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-2. Using the midpoint method, if the price falls from $80 to $60, the absolute value of the price elasticity of demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "20.",
                        "10.",
                        "2.33.",
                        "0.43."
                    ],
                    "answer": "2.33.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 103,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-2. Using the midpoint method, if the price falls from $60 to $40, the absolute value of the price elasticity of demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "0.4.",
                        "1.",
                        "4.",
                        "20."
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 104,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-2. Using the midpoint method, if the price falls from $40 to $20, the absolute value of the price elasticity of demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "20.",
                        "10.",
                        "2.33.",
                        "0.43."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.43.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 105,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-2. Using the midpoint method, if the price falls from $80 to $60, the price elasticity of demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "zero.",
                        "unit elastic.",
                        "inelastic.",
                        "elastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "elastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 106,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-2. Using the midpoint method, if the price falls from $60 to $40, the price elasticity of demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "zero.",
                        "inelastic.",
                        "unit elastic.",
                        "elastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "unit elastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 107,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-2. Using the midpoint method, if the price falls from $40 to $20, the price elasticity of demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "zero.",
                        "inelastic.",
                        "unit elastic.",
                        "elastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "inelastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 108,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-3. Using the midpoint method, what is the price elasticity of demand when price rises from $9 to $12?",
                    "options": [
                        "0.43",
                        "0.67",
                        "1.50",
                        "2.33"
                    ],
                    "answer": "2.33",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 109,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-3. Using the midpoint method, when price rises from $6 to $9, the price elasticity of demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "0.43",
                        "0.67",
                        "1.00",
                        "1.5"
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.00",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 110,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-3. Using the midpoint method, when price falls from $6 to $3, the price elasticity of demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "0.43",
                        "0.67",
                        "1.50",
                        "2.33"
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.43",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 111,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-4. As price rises from $10 to $12, the price elasticity of demand using the midpoint method is approximately",
                    "options": [
                        "0.08.",
                        "0.18.",
                        "0.42.",
                        "0.58."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.58.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 112,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-4. Demand is unit elastic when quantity demanded changes from",
                    "options": [
                        "10 to 9.",
                        "9 to 8.",
                        "8 to 7.",
                        "There is not enough information given to determine the correct answer."
                    ],
                    "answer": "8 to 7.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 113,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-4. When price is between $10 and $14, demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "elastic.",
                        "unit elastic.",
                        "inelastic.",
                        "There is not enough information given to determine whether demand is elastic, unit elastic, or inelastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "inelastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 114,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-1. Between point A and point B, price elasticity of demand is equal to",
                    "options": [
                        "0.33.",
                        "0.67.",
                        "1.5",
                        "2.67."
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.5",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 115,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-1. Between point A and point B, the slope is equal to",
                    "options": [
                        "-1/4, and the price elasticity of demand is equal to 2/3.",
                        "-1/4, and the price elasticity of demand is equal to 3/2.",
                        "-3/2, and the price elasticity of demand is equal to 1/4.",
                        "-2/3, and the price elasticity of demand is equal to 3/2."
                    ],
                    "answer": "-1/4, and the price elasticity of demand is equal to 3/2.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 116,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-1. Between point A and point B on the graph, demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "perfectly elastic.",
                        "inelastic.",
                        "unit elastic.",
                        "elastic, but not perfectly elastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "elastic, but not perfectly elastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 117,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose demand is perfectly elastic, and the supply of the good in question decreases. As a result,",
                    "options": [
                        "the equilibrium quantity decreases, and the equilibrium price is unchanged.",
                        "the equilibrium price increases, and the equilibrium quantity is unchanged.",
                        "the equilibrium quantity and the equilibrium price both are unchanged.",
                        "buyers' total expenditure on the good is unchanged."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the equilibrium quantity decreases, and the equilibrium price is unchanged.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 118,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A perfectly elastic demand implies that",
                    "options": [
                        "buyers will not respond to any change in price.",
                        "any rise in price above that represented by the demand curve will result in a quantity demanded of zero.",
                        "quantity demanded and price change by the same percent as we move along the demand curve.",
                        "price will rise by an infinite amount when there is a change in quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "any rise in price above that represented by the demand curve will result in a quantity demanded of zero.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 119,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The case of perfectly elastic demand is illustrated by a demand curve that is",
                    "options": [
                        "vertical.",
                        "horizontal.",
                        "downward-sloping but relatively steep.",
                        "downward-sloping but relatively flat."
                    ],
                    "answer": "horizontal.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 120,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When small changes in price lead to infinite changes in quantity demanded, demand is perfectly",
                    "options": [
                        "elastic, and the demand curve will be horizontal.",
                        "inelastic, and the demand curve will be horizontal.",
                        "elastic, and the demand curve will be vertical.",
                        "inelastic, and the demand curve will be vertical."
                    ],
                    "answer": "elastic, and the demand curve will be horizontal.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 121,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For a horizontal demand curve,",
                    "options": [
                        "the slope is undefined, and the price elasticity of demand is equal to 0.",
                        "the slope is equal to 0, and the price elasticity of demand is undefined.",
                        "both the slope and price elasticity of demand are undefined.",
                        "both the slope and price elasticity of demand are equal to 0."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the slope is equal to 0, and the price elasticity of demand is undefined.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 122,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose demand is perfectly inelastic, and the supply of the good in question decreases. As a result,",
                    "options": [
                        "the equilibrium quantity decreases, and the equilibrium price is unchanged.",
                        "the equilibrium price increases, and the equilibrium quantity is unchanged.",
                        "the equilibrium quantity and the equilibrium price both are unchanged.",
                        "buyers' total expenditure on the good is unchanged."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the equilibrium price increases, and the equilibrium quantity is unchanged.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 123,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In the case of perfectly inelastic demand,",
                    "options": [
                        "the change in quantity demanded equals the change in price.",
                        "the percentage change in quantity demanded equals the percentage change in price.",
                        "infinitely-large changes in quantity demanded result from very small changes in the price.",
                        "quantity demanded stays the same whenever price changes."
                    ],
                    "answer": "quantity demanded stays the same whenever price changes.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 124,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When demand is perfectly inelastic, the demand curve will be",
                    "options": [
                        "negatively sloped, because buyers decrease their purchases when the price rises.",
                        "vertical, because buyers purchase the same amount as before whenever the price rises or falls.",
                        "positively sloped, because buyers increase their purchases when price rises.",
                        "positively sloped, because buyers increase their total expenditures when price rises."
                    ],
                    "answer": "vertical, because buyers purchase the same amount as before whenever the price rises or falls.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 125,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When demand is perfectly inelastic, the price elasticity of demand",
                    "options": [
                        "is zero, and the demand curve is vertical.",
                        "is zero, and the demand curve is horizontal.",
                        "approaches infinity, and the demand curve is vertical.",
                        "approaches infinity, and the demand curve is horizontal."
                    ],
                    "answer": "is zero, and the demand curve is vertical.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 126,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A perfectly inelastic demand implies that buyers",
                    "options": [
                        "decrease their purchases when the price rises.",
                        "purchase the same amount as before when the price rises or falls.",
                        "increase their purchases only slightly when the price falls.",
                        "respond substantially to an increase in price."
                    ],
                    "answer": "purchase the same amount as before when the price rises or falls.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 127,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Ryan says that he would buy one cup of coffee every day regardless of the price. If he is telling the truth, Ryan's",
                    "options": [
                        "demand for coffee is perfectly inelastic.",
                        "price elasticity of demand for coffee is 1.",
                        "income elasticity of demand for coffee is 0.",
                        "None of the above answers is correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "demand for coffee is perfectly inelastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 128,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For a vertical demand curve,",
                    "options": [
                        "the slope is undefined, and the price elasticity of demand is equal to 0.",
                        "the slope is equal to 0, and the price elasticity of demand is undefined.",
                        "both the slope and price elasticity of demand are undefined.",
                        "both the slope and price elasticity of demand are equal to 0."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the slope is undefined, and the price elasticity of demand is equal to 0.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 129,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In which of these instances is demand said to be perfectly inelastic?",
                    "options": [
                        "An increase in price of 2% causes a decrease in quantity demanded of 2%.",
                        "A decrease in price of 2% causes an increase in quantity demanded of 0%.",
                        "A decrease in price of 2% causes a decrease in total revenue of 0%.",
                        "An increase in price of 2% causes a decrease in quantity demanded of 1/2%."
                    ],
                    "answer": "A decrease in price of 2% causes an increase in quantity demanded of 0%.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 130,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Demand is said to have unit elasticity if the price elasticity of demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "less than 1.",
                        "greater than 1.",
                        "equal to 1.",
                        "equal to 0."
                    ],
                    "answer": "equal to 1.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 131,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Demand is said to be unit elastic if quantity demanded",
                    "options": [
                        "changes by the same percent as the price.",
                        "changes by a larger percent than the price.",
                        "changes by a smaller percent than the price.",
                        "does not respond to a change in price."
                    ],
                    "answer": "changes by the same percent as the price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 132,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When quantity moves proportionately the same amount as price, demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "elastic, and the price elasticity of demand is 1.",
                        "perfectly elastic, and the price elasticity of demand is infinitely large.",
                        "perfectly inelastic, and the price elasticity of demand is 0.",
                        "unit elastic, and the price elasticity of demand is 1."
                    ],
                    "answer": "unit elastic, and the price elasticity of demand is 1.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 133,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Pierre says that he will spend exactly 75 cents a day on candy bars, regardless of the price of candy bars. Pierre's demand for candy bars is",
                    "options": [
                        "perfectly elastic.",
                        "unit elastic.",
                        "perfectly inelastic.",
                        "None of the above answers is correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "unit elastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 134,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When we move upward and to the left along a linear, downward-sloping demand curve, price elasticity of demand",
                    "options": [
                        "first becomes smaller, then larger.",
                        "always becomes larger.",
                        "always becomes smaller.",
                        "first becomes larger, then smaller."
                    ],
                    "answer": "always becomes larger.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 135,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The price elasticity of demand changes as we move along a",
                    "options": [
                        "horizontal demand curve.",
                        "vertical demand curve.",
                        "linear, downward-sloping demand curve.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "linear, downward-sloping demand curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 136,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If a 15% increase in price for a good results in a 20% decrease in quantity demanded, the price elasticity of demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "0.75.",
                        "1.25.",
                        "1.33.",
                        "1.60."
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.33.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 137,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If a 20% increase in price for a good results in a 15% decrease in quantity demanded, the price elasticity of demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "0.75.",
                        "1.25.",
                        "1.33.",
                        "1.60."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.75.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 138,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If a 10% decrease in price for a good results in a 20% increase in quantity demanded, the price elasticity of demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "0.50.",
                        "1.",
                        "1.5.",
                        "2."
                    ],
                    "answer": "2.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 139,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If a 6% decrease in price for a good results in a 2% increase in quantity demanded, the price elasticity of demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "0.02.",
                        "0.33.",
                        "3.",
                        "4."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.33.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 140,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-2. As price falls from Pa to Pb, which demand curve represents the most elastic demand?",
                    "options": [
                        "D1",
                        "D2",
                        "D3",
                        "All of the above are equally elastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "D1",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 141,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-2. As price falls from Pa to Pb, we could use the three demand curves to calculate three different values of the price elasticity of demand. Which of the three demand curves would produce the smallest elasticity?",
                    "options": [
                        "D1",
                        "D2",
                        "D3",
                        "All of the above are equally elastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "D3",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 142,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-3. The demand curve representing the demand for a luxury good with several close substitutes is",
                    "options": [
                        "A.",
                        "B.",
                        "C.",
                        "D."
                    ],
                    "answer": "C.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 143,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-3. Mark says he would buy one Mt. Dew per day regardless of the price. If this is true, then Mark's demand for Mt. Dew is represented by demand curve",
                    "options": [
                        "A.",
                        "B.",
                        "C.",
                        "D."
                    ],
                    "answer": "A.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 144,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-3. Which demand curve is perfectly elastic?",
                    "options": [
                        "A",
                        "B",
                        "C",
                        "D"
                    ],
                    "answer": "D",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 145,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-3. Which demand curve is perfectly inelastic?",
                    "options": [
                        "A",
                        "B",
                        "C",
                        "D"
                    ],
                    "answer": "A",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 146,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-3. Which demand curve is unit elastic?",
                    "options": [
                        "A",
                        "B",
                        "D",
                        "None of the above."
                    ],
                    "answer": "None of the above.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 147,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When the price of good A is $50, the quantity demanded of good A is 500 units. When the price of good A rises to $70, the quantity demanded of good A falls to 400 units. Using the midpoint method, the price elasticity of demand for good A is",
                    "options": [
                        "1.50, and an increase in price will result in an increase in total revenue for good A.",
                        "1.50, and an increase in price will result in a decrease in total revenue for good A.",
                        "0.67, and an increase in price will result in an increase in total revenue for good A.",
                        "0.67, and an increase in price will result in a decrease in total revenue for good A."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.67, and an increase in price will result in an increase in total revenue for good A.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 148,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Consider luxury weekend hotel packages in Las Vegas. When the price is $250, the quantity demanded is 2,000 packages per week. When the price is $280, the quantity demanded is 1,700 packages per week. Using the midpoint method, the price elasticity of demand is about",
                    "options": [
                        "1.43, and an increase in the price will cause hotels' total revenue to decrease.",
                        "1.43, and an increase in the price will cause hotels' total revenue to increase.",
                        "0.70, and an increase in the price will cause hotels' total revenue to decrease.",
                        "0.70, and an increase in the price will cause hotels' total revenue to increase."
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.43, and an increase in the price will cause hotels' total revenue to decrease.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 149,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When the local used bookstore prices economics books at $15 each, it generally sells 70 books per month. If it lowers the price to $7, sales increase to 90 books per month. Given this information, we know that the price elasticity of demand for economics books is about",
                    "options": [
                        "2.91, and an increase in price from $7 to $15 results in an increase in total revenue.",
                        "2.91, and an increase in price from $7 to $15 results in a decrease in total revenue.",
                        "0.34, and an increase in price from $7 to $15 results in an increase in total revenue.",
                        "0.34, and an increase in price from $7 to $15 results in a decrease in total revenue."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.34, and an increase in price from $7 to $15 results in an increase in total revenue.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 150,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Fiona's Fish Emporium increased its total monthly revenue from $1,500 to $1,800 when it raised the price of tropical fish from $5 to $9. The price elasticity of demand for Fiona's Fish Emporium is",
                    "options": [
                        "0.57.",
                        "0.70.",
                        "1.43.",
                        "2.20."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.70.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 151,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Melvin's Magnets earned $200 in total revenue last month when it sold 100 souvenir magnets. This month it earned $300 in total revenue when it sold 60 souvenir magnets. The price elasticity of demand for Marvin's Magnets is",
                    "options": [
                        "0.27.",
                        "0.58.",
                        "1.25.",
                        "1.71."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.58.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 152,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that when the price of wheat is $2 per bushel, farmers can sell 10 million bushels. When the price of wheat is $3 per bushel, farmers can sell 8 million bushels. Which of the following statements is true? The demand for wheat is",
                    "options": [
                        "income inelastic, so an increase in the price of wheat will increase the total revenue of wheat farmers.",
                        "income elastic, so an increase in the price of wheat will increase the total revenue of wheat farmers.",
                        "price inelastic, so an increase in the price of wheat will increase the total revenue of wheat farmers.",
                        "price elastic, so an increase in the price of wheat will increase the total revenue of wheat farmers."
                    ],
                    "answer": "price inelastic, so an increase in the price of wheat will increase the total revenue of wheat farmers.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 153,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that when the price of ginger ale is $2 per bottle, firms can sell 4 million bottles. When the price of ginger ale is $3 per bottle, firms can sell 2 million bottles. Which of the following statements is true?",
                    "options": [
                        "The demand for ginger ale is income inelastic, so an increase in the price of ginger ale will increase the total revenue of ginger ale producers.",
                        "The demand for ginger ale is income elastic, so an increase in the price of ginger ale will increase the total revenue of ginger ale producers.",
                        "The demand for ginger ale is price inelastic, so an increase in the price of ginger ale will increase the total revenue of ginger ale producers.",
                        "The demand for ginger ale is price elastic, so an increase in the price of ginger ale will decrease the total revenue of ginger ale producers."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The demand for ginger ale is price elastic, so an increase in the price of ginger ale will decrease the total revenue of ginger ale producers.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 154,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that 50 hot dogs are demanded at a particular price. If the price of hot dogs rises from that price by 5 percent, the number of hot dogs demanded falls to 48. Using the midpoint approach to calculate the price elasticity of demand, it follows that the",
                    "options": [
                        "demand for hot dogs in this price range is unit elastic.",
                        "price increase will decrease the total revenue of hot dog sellers.",
                        "price elasticity of demand for hot dogs in this price range is about 1.22.",
                        "price elasticity of demand for hot dogs in this price range is about 0.82."
                    ],
                    "answer": "price elasticity of demand for hot dogs in this price range is about 0.82.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 155,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that 500 candy bars are demanded at a particular price. If the price of candy bars rises from that price by 10 percent, the number of candy bars demanded falls to 480. Using the midpoint approach to calculate the price elasticity of demand, it follows that the",
                    "options": [
                        "demand for candy bars in this price range is unit elastic.",
                        "price increase will decrease the total revenue of candy bar sellers.",
                        "price elasticity of demand for candy bars in this price range is about 0.41.",
                        "price elasticity of demand for candy bars in this price range is about 0.24."
                    ],
                    "answer": "price elasticity of demand for candy bars in this price range is about 0.41.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 156,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "An increase in price causes an increase in total revenue when demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "elastic.",
                        "inelastic.",
                        "unit elastic.",
                        "All of the above are possible."
                    ],
                    "answer": "inelastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 157,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The local bakery makes such great cinnamon rolls that consumers do not respond much at all to a change in the price. If the owner is only interested in increasing revenue, she should",
                    "options": [
                        "lower the price of the cinnamon rolls.",
                        "leave the price of the cinnamon rolls unchanged.",
                        "raise the price of the cinnamon rolls.",
                        "reduce costs."
                    ],
                    "answer": "raise the price of the cinnamon rolls.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 158,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that demand is inelastic within a certain price range. For that price range,",
                    "options": [
                        "an increase in price would increase total revenue because the decrease in quantity demanded is proportionately less than the increase in price.",
                        "an increase in price would decrease total revenue because the decrease in quantity demanded is proportionately greater than the increase in price.",
                        "a decrease in price would increase total revenue because the increase in quantity demanded is proportionately smaller than the decrease in price.",
                        "a decrease in price would not affect total revenue."
                    ],
                    "answer": "an increase in price would increase total revenue because the decrease in quantity demanded is proportionately less than the increase in price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 159,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When demand is inelastic, the price elasticity of demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "less than 1, and price and total revenue will move in the same direction.",
                        "less than 1, and price and total revenue will move in opposite directions.",
                        "greater than 1, and price and total revenue will move in the same direction.",
                        "greater than 1, and price and total revenue will move in opposite directions."
                    ],
                    "answer": "less than 1, and price and total revenue will move in the same direction.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 160,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "How does total revenue change as one moves downward and to the right along a linear demand curve?",
                    "options": [
                        "It always increases.",
                        "It always decreases.",
                        "It first increases, then decreases.",
                        "It is unaffected by a movement along the demand curve."
                    ],
                    "answer": "It first increases, then decreases.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 161,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "On a downward-sloping linear demand curve, total revenue reaches its maximum value at the",
                    "options": [
                        "midpoint of the demand curve.",
                        "lower end of the demand curve.",
                        "upper end of the demand curve.",
                        "It is impossible to tell without knowing prices and quantities demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "midpoint of the demand curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 162,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A city wants to raise revenues to build a new municipal swimming pool next year. The mayor suggests that the city raise the price of admission to the current municipal pools this year to raise revenues. The city manager suggests that the city lower the price of admission to raise revenues. Who is correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "the mayor",
                        "the city manager",
                        "The answer depends on the price elasticity of demand.",
                        "The answer depends on the costs of construction of the new municipal swimming pool."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The answer depends on the price elasticity of demand.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 163,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A city wants to raise revenues to build a new municipal swimming pool next year. The mayor suggests that the city raise the price of admission to the current municipal pools this year to raise revenues. The city manager suggests that the city lower the price of admission to raise revenues. Who is correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "Both the mayor and city manager would be correct if demand were price elastic.",
                        "Both the mayor and city manager would be correct if demand were price inelastic.",
                        "The mayor would be correct if demand were price elastic; the city manager would be correct if demand were price inelastic.",
                        "The mayor would be correct if demand were price inelastic; the city manager would be correct if demand were price elastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The mayor would be correct if demand were price inelastic; the city manager would be correct if demand were price elastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 164,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When demand is inelastic, a decrease in price will cause",
                    "options": [
                        "an increase in total revenue.",
                        "a decrease in total revenue.",
                        "no change in total revenue but an increase in quantity demanded.",
                        "no change in total revenue but a decrease in quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "a decrease in total revenue.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 165,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When demand is elastic, a decrease in price will cause",
                    "options": [
                        "an increase in total revenue.",
                        "a decrease in total revenue.",
                        "no change in total revenue but an increase in quantity demanded.",
                        "no change in total revenue but a decrease in quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "an increase in total revenue.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 166,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When demand is inelastic, an increase in price will cause",
                    "options": [
                        "an increase in total revenue.",
                        "a decrease in total revenue.",
                        "no change in total revenue but an increase in quantity demanded.",
                        "no change in total revenue but a decrease in quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "an increase in total revenue.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 167,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When demand is elastic, an increase in price will cause",
                    "options": [
                        "an increase in total revenue.",
                        "a decrease in total revenue.",
                        "no change in total revenue but an increase in quantity demanded.",
                        "no change in total revenue but a decrease in quantity demanded."
                    ],
                    "answer": "a decrease in total revenue.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 168,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following could be the price elasticity of demand for a good for which a decrease in price would increase revenue?",
                    "options": [
                        "0",
                        "0.2",
                        "1",
                        "2.1"
                    ],
                    "answer": "2.1",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 169,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following could be the price elasticity of demand for a good for which an increase in price would increase revenue?",
                    "options": [
                        "0.2",
                        "1",
                        "1.5",
                        "All of the above could be correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.2",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 170,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following could be the price elasticity of demand for a good for which a decrease in price would decrease revenue?",
                    "options": [
                        "0.5",
                        "1",
                        "1.5",
                        "All of the above could be correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.5",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 171,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following could be the price elasticity of demand for a good for which an increase in price would decrease revenue?",
                    "options": [
                        "0",
                        "0.5",
                        "1",
                        "1.5"
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.5",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 172,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is not possible?",
                    "options": [
                        "Demand is elastic, and a decrease in price causes an increase in revenue.",
                        "Demand is unit elastic, and a decrease in price causes an increase in revenue.",
                        "Demand is inelastic, and an increase in price causes an increase in revenue.",
                        "Demand is perfectly inelastic, and an increase in price causes an increase in revenue."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Demand is unit elastic, and a decrease in price causes an increase in revenue.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 173,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If demand is price inelastic, then when price rises, total revenue",
                    "options": [
                        "will fall.",
                        "will rise.",
                        "will remain unchanged.",
                        "may rise, fall, or remain unchanged. More information is need to determine the change in total revenue with certainty."
                    ],
                    "answer": "will rise.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 174,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price elasticity of demand for tuna is 0.7, then a 1.5% increase in the price of tuna will decrease the quantity demanded of tuna by",
                    "options": [
                        "1.05%, and tuna sellers' total revenue will increase as a result.",
                        "1.05%, and tuna sellers' total revenue will decrease as a result.",
                        "2.14%, and tuna sellers' total revenue will increase as a result.",
                        "2.14%, and tuna sellers' total revenue will decrease as a result."
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.05%, and tuna sellers' total revenue will increase as a result.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 175,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price elasticity of demand for aluminum foil is 1.45, then a 2.4% decrease in the price of aluminum foil will increase the quantity demanded of aluminum foil by",
                    "options": [
                        "1.66%, and aluminum foil sellers' total revenue will increase as a result.",
                        "1.66%, and aluminum foil sellers' total revenue will decrease as a result.",
                        "3.48%, and aluminum foil sellers' total revenue will increase as a result.",
                        "3.48%, and aluminum foil sellers' total revenue will decrease as a result."
                    ],
                    "answer": "3.48%, and aluminum foil sellers' total revenue will increase as a result.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 176,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If a change in the price of a good results in no change in total revenue, then",
                    "options": [
                        "the demand for the good must be elastic.",
                        "the demand for the good must be inelastic.",
                        "the demand for the good must be unit elastic.",
                        "buyers must not respond very much to a change in price."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the demand for the good must be unit elastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 177,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When demand is unit elastic, price elasticity of demand equals",
                    "options": [
                        "1, and total revenue and price move in the same direction.",
                        "1, and total revenue and price move in opposite directions.",
                        "1, and total revenue does not change when price changes.",
                        "0, and total revenue does not change when price changes."
                    ],
                    "answer": "1, and total revenue does not change when price changes.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 178,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the demand curve is linear and downward sloping, which of the following statements is not correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "Demand is more elastic on the lower part of the demand curve than on the upper part.",
                        "Different pairs of points on the demand curve can result in different values of the price elasticity of demand.",
                        "Different pairs of points on the demand curve result in identical values of the slope of the demand curve.",
                        "Starting from a point on the upper part of the demand curve, an increase in price leads to a decrease in total revenue."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Demand is more elastic on the lower part of the demand curve than on the upper part.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 179,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Total revenue",
                    "options": [
                        "always increases as price increases.",
                        "increases as price increases, as long as demand is elastic.",
                        "decreases as price increases, as long as demand is inelastic.",
                        "remains unchanged as price increases when demand is unit elastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "remains unchanged as price increases when demand is unit elastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 180,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In which of the following situations will total revenue increase?",
                    "options": [
                        "Price elasticity of demand is 1.2, and the price of the good decreases.",
                        "Price elasticity of demand is 0.5, and the price of the good increases.",
                        "Price elasticity of demand is 3.0, and the price of the good decreases.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 181,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You have just been hired as a business consultant to determine what pricing policy would be appropriate in order to increase the total revenue of a bakery. The first step you would take would be to",
                    "options": [
                        "increase the price of every loaf of bread in the store.",
                        "look for ways to cut costs and increase profit for the bakery.",
                        "determine the price elasticity of demand for the bakery's products.",
                        "determine the price elasticity of supply for the bakery's products."
                    ],
                    "answer": "determine the price elasticity of demand for the bakery's products.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 182,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You are in charge of the local city-owned aquatic center. You need to increase the revenue generated by the aquatic center in order to meet expenses. The mayor advises you to increase the price of a day pass. The city manager recommends reducing the price of a day pass. You realize that",
                    "options": [
                        "the mayor thinks demand is elastic, and the city manager thinks demand is inelastic.",
                        "both the mayor and the city manager think that demand is elastic.",
                        "both the mayor and the city manager think that demand is inelastic.",
                        "the mayor thinks demand is inelastic, and the city manager thinks demand is elastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the mayor thinks demand is inelastic, and the city manager thinks demand is elastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 183,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You are in charge of the local city-owned aquatic center. You need to increase the revenue generated by the aquatic center in order to meet expenses. The mayor advises you to decrease the price of a day pass. The city manager recommends increasing the price of a day pass. You realize that",
                    "options": [
                        "the mayor thinks demand is elastic, and the city manager thinks demand is inelastic.",
                        "both the mayor and the city manager think that demand is elastic.",
                        "both the mayor and the city manager think that demand is inelastic.",
                        "the mayor thinks demand is inelastic, and the city manager thinks demand is elastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the mayor thinks demand is elastic, and the city manager thinks demand is inelastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 184,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Get Smart University is contemplating an increase in tuition to enhance revenue. If GSU feels that raising tuition would enhance revenue, it is",
                    "options": [
                        "ignoring the law of demand.",
                        "assuming that the demand for university education is elastic.",
                        "assuming that the demand for university education is inelastic.",
                        "assuming that the supply of university education is elastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "assuming that the demand for university education is inelastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 185,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the demand for donuts is elastic, then a decrease in the price of donuts will",
                    "options": [
                        "increase total revenue of donut sellers.",
                        "decrease total revenue of donut sellers.",
                        "not change total revenue of donut sellers.",
                        "There is not enough information to answer this question."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase total revenue of donut sellers.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 186,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the demand for apples is elastic, then an increase in the price of apples will",
                    "options": [
                        "increase total revenue of apple sellers.",
                        "decrease total revenue of apple sellers.",
                        "not change total revenue of apple sellers.",
                        "There is not enough information to answer this question."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease total revenue of apple sellers.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 187,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the demand for textbooks is inelastic, then a decrease in the price of textbooks will",
                    "options": [
                        "increase total revenue of textbook sellers.",
                        "decrease total revenue of textbook sellers.",
                        "not change total revenue of textbook sellers.",
                        "There is not enough information to answer this question."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease total revenue of textbook sellers.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 188,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the demand for textbooks is inelastic, then an increase in the price of textbooks will",
                    "options": [
                        "increase total revenue of textbook sellers.",
                        "decrease total revenue of textbook sellers.",
                        "not change total revenue of textbook sellers.",
                        "There is not enough information to answer this question."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase total revenue of textbook sellers.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 189,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Kevin tunes pianos. If the demand for piano-tuning services is elastic, Kevin could increase his total revenue by",
                    "options": [
                        "increasing the price of his piano-tuning services.",
                        "decreasing the price of his piano-tuning services.",
                        "leaving the price of his piano-tuning services unchanged.",
                        "None of the above is correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decreasing the price of his piano-tuning services.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 190,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Holding all other forces constant, if increasing the price of a good leads to an increase in total revenue, then the demand for the good must be",
                    "options": [
                        "unit elastic.",
                        "inelastic.",
                        "elastic.",
                        "None of the above is correct because a price increase always leads to an increase in total revenue."
                    ],
                    "answer": "inelastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 191,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Holding all other forces constant, if increasing the price of a good leads to a decrease in total revenue, then the demand for the good must be",
                    "options": [
                        "unit elastic.",
                        "inelastic.",
                        "elastic.",
                        "None of the above is correct because a price increase always leads to an increase in total revenue."
                    ],
                    "answer": "elastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 192,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Holding all other forces constant, if decreasing the price of a good leads to an increase in total revenue, then the demand for the good must be",
                    "options": [
                        "unit elastic.",
                        "inelastic.",
                        "elastic.",
                        "None of the above is correct because a price increase always leads to an increase in total revenue."
                    ],
                    "answer": "elastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 193,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Holding all other forces constant, if decreasing the price of a good leads to a decrease in total revenue, then the demand for the good must be",
                    "options": [
                        "unit elastic.",
                        "inelastic.",
                        "elastic.",
                        "None of the above is correct because a price increase always leads to an increase in total revenue."
                    ],
                    "answer": "inelastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 194,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose you are in charge of setting prices at a local sandwich shop. The business needs to increase its total revenue, and your job is on the line. If the demand for sandwiches is elastic, you",
                    "options": [
                        "should increase the price of sandwiches.",
                        "should decrease the price of sandwiches.",
                        "should not change the price of sandwiches.",
                        "could not determine what to do with price until you determine whether supply is elastic or inelastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "should decrease the price of sandwiches.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 195,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose a producer is able to separate customers into two groups, one having an inelastic demand and the other having an elastic demand. If the producer's objective is to increase total revenue, she should",
                    "options": [
                        "increase the price charged to customers with the elastic demand and decrease the price charged to customers with the inelastic demand.",
                        "decrease the price charged to customers with the elastic demand and increase the price charged to customers with the inelastic demand.",
                        "decrease the price to both groups of customers.",
                        "increase the price for both groups of customers."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease the price charged to customers with the elastic demand and increase the price charged to customers with the inelastic demand.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 196,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Your younger sister needs $50 to buy a new bike. She has opened a lemonade stand to make the money she needs. Your mother is paying for all of the ingredients. She currently is charging 25 cents per cup, but she wants to adjust her price to earn the $50 faster. If you know that the demand for lemonade is elastic, what is your advice to her?",
                    "options": [
                        "Leave the price at 25 cents and be patient.",
                        "Raise the price to increase total revenue.",
                        "Lower the price to increase total revenue.",
                        "There isn't enough information given to answer this question."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Lower the price to increase total revenue.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 197,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose the point (Q = 2,000, P = $60) is the midpoint on a certain downward-sloping, linear demand curve. Then",
                    "options": [
                        "an increase in price from $40 to $42 will increase total revenue.",
                        "a decrease in price from $61 to $59 will leave total revenue unchanged.",
                        "the maximum value of total revenue is $120,000.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 198,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Moving downward and to the right along a linear demand curve, we know that total revenue",
                    "options": [
                        "first increases, then decreases.",
                        "first decreases, then increases.",
                        "always increases.",
                        "always decreases."
                    ],
                    "answer": "first increases, then decreases.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 199,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Total revenue will be at its largest value on a linear demand curve at the",
                    "options": [
                        "top of the curve, where prices are highest.",
                        "midpoint of the curve.",
                        "low end of the curve, where quantity demanded is highest.",
                        "None of the above is correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "midpoint of the curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 200,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-4. Suppose the point labeled B is the \"halfway point\" on the demand curve and it corresponds to a price of $5.00. Then, between prices of $4.99 and $5.01, the price elasticity of demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "less than 1 but greater than zero.",
                        "equal to 1.",
                        "greater than 1.",
                        "equal to zero."
                    ],
                    "answer": "equal to 1.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 201,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-4. The section of the demand curve from A to B represents the",
                    "options": [
                        "elastic section of the demand curve.",
                        "inelastic section of the demand curve.",
                        "unit elastic section of the demand curve.",
                        "perfectly elastic section of the demand curve."
                    ],
                    "answer": "elastic section of the demand curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 202,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-4. The section of the demand curve from B to C represents the",
                    "options": [
                        "elastic section of the demand curve.",
                        "inelastic section of the demand curve.",
                        "unit elastic section of the demand curve.",
                        "perfectly elastic section of the demand curve."
                    ],
                    "answer": "inelastic section of the demand curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 203,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-4. The section of the demand curve at point B represents the",
                    "options": [
                        "elastic section of the demand curve.",
                        "inelastic section of the demand curve.",
                        "unit elastic section of the demand curve.",
                        "perfectly elastic section of the demand curve."
                    ],
                    "answer": "unit elastic section of the demand curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 204,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-4. Assume the section of the demand curve from A to B corresponds to prices between $8 and $16. Then, when the price changes between $9 and $10,",
                    "options": [
                        "quantity demanded changes proportionately less than the price.",
                        "quantity demanded changes proportionately more than the price.",
                        "quantity demanded changes the same amount proportionately as price.",
                        "the price elasticity of demand equals 1."
                    ],
                    "answer": "quantity demanded changes proportionately more than the price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 205,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-4. Assume the section of the demand curve from A to B corresponds to prices between $6 and $12. Then, when the price increases from $8 to $10,",
                    "options": [
                        "the percent decrease in the quantity demanded exceeds the percent increase in the price.",
                        "the percent increase in the price exceeds the percent decrease in the quantity demanded.",
                        "sellers' total revenue increases as a result.",
                        "it is possible that the quantity demanded fell from 550 to 500 as a result."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the percent decrease in the quantity demanded exceeds the percent increase in the price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 206,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-4. Assume, for the good in question, two specific points on the demand curve are (Q = 1,000, P = $40) and (Q = 1,500, P = $30). Then which of the following scenarios is possible?",
                    "options": [
                        "Both of these points lie on the section of the demand curve from B to C.",
                        "The vertical intercept of the demand curve is the point (Q = 0, P = $60).",
                        "The horizontal intercept of the demand curve is the point (Q = 1,800, P = $0).",
                        "Any of these scenarios is possible."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The vertical intercept of the demand curve is the point (Q = 0, P = $60).",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 207,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-4. The section of the demand curve from B to C represents the",
                    "options": [
                        "elastic section of the demand curve.",
                        "perfectly elastic section of the demand curve.",
                        "unit elastic section of the demand curve.",
                        "inelastic section of the demand curve."
                    ],
                    "answer": "inelastic section of the demand curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 208,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-4. Assume the section of the demand curve from B to C corresponds to prices between $0 and $15. Then, when the price changes between $7 and $9,",
                    "options": [
                        "quantity demanded changes proportionately less than the price.",
                        "quantity demanded changes proportionately more than the price.",
                        "quantity demanded changes the same amount proportionately as price.",
                        "the price elasticity of demand equals zero."
                    ],
                    "answer": "quantity demanded changes proportionately less than the price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 209,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-4. Assume, for the good in question, two specific points on the demand curve are (Q = 2,000, P = $15) and (Q = 2,400, P = $12). Then which of the following scenarios is possible?",
                    "options": [
                        "Both of these points lie on section BC of the demand curve.",
                        "The vertical intercept of the demand curve is the point (Q = 0, P = $22).",
                        "The horizontal intercept of the demand curve is the point (Q = 5,000, P = $0).",
                        "Any of these scenarios is possible."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Both of these points lie on section BC of the demand curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 210,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-4. If the price decreases in the region of the demand curve between points A and B, we can expect total revenue to",
                    "options": [
                        "increase.",
                        "stay the same.",
                        "decrease.",
                        "first decrease, then increase until total revenue is maximized."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 211,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-4. If the price increases in the region of the demand curve between points A and B, we can expect total revenue to",
                    "options": [
                        "increase.",
                        "stay the same.",
                        "decrease.",
                        "first increase, then decrease until total revenue is maximized."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 212,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-4. If the price decreases in the region of the demand curve between points B and C, we can expect total revenue to",
                    "options": [
                        "increase.",
                        "stay the same.",
                        "decrease.",
                        "first increase, then decrease until total revenue is maximized."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 213,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-4. If the price increases in the region of the demand curve between points B and C, we can expect total revenue to",
                    "options": [
                        "increase.",
                        "stay the same.",
                        "decrease.",
                        "first decrease, then increase until total revenue is maximized."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 214,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-5. Using the midpoint method, demand is unit elastic between prices of",
                    "options": [
                        "$18 and $24.",
                        "$24 and $30.",
                        "$24 and $36.",
                        "$30 and $36."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$24 and $36.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 215,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-5. Using the midpoint method, between prices of $12 and $18, price elasticity of demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "0.33.",
                        "0.67.",
                        "1.33.",
                        "1.89."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.33.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 216,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-5. Using the midpoint method, between prices of $48 and $54, price elasticity of demand is about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.92.",
                        "3.89.",
                        "4.33.",
                        "5.67."
                    ],
                    "answer": "5.67.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 217,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-5. Using the midpoint method, between prices of $30 and $36, price elasticity of demand is about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.5.",
                        "0.82.",
                        "1.22.",
                        "2."
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.22.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 218,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-5. The maximum value of total revenue corresponds to a price of",
                    "options": [
                        "$18.",
                        "$30.",
                        "$42.",
                        "$48."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$30.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 219,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-5. At a price of $48 per unit, sellers' total revenue equals",
                    "options": [
                        "$150.",
                        "$200.",
                        "$288.",
                        "$364."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$288.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 220,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-5. At a price of $12 per unit, sellers' total revenue equals",
                    "options": [
                        "$150.",
                        "$200.",
                        "$288.",
                        "$364."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$288.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 221,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-5. At a price of $30 per unit, sellers' total revenue equals",
                    "options": [
                        "$150.",
                        "$200.",
                        "$288.",
                        "$450."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$450.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 222,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-6. Using the midpoint method, the price elasticity of demand between point A and point B is",
                    "options": [
                        "1.",
                        "1.5.",
                        "2.",
                        "2.5."
                    ],
                    "answer": "2.5.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 223,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-6. Using the midpoint method, the price elasticity of demand between point B and point C is",
                    "options": [
                        "0.5.",
                        "0.75.",
                        "1.0.",
                        "1.3."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.75.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 224,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-6. If the price decreased from $18 to $6, total revenue would",
                    "options": [
                        "increase by $1,200, and demand is elastic between points A and C.",
                        "increase by $800, and demand is elastic between points A and C.",
                        "decrease by $1,200, and demand is inelastic between points A and C.",
                        "decrease by $800, and demand is inelastic between points A and C."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase by $1,200, and demand is elastic between points A and C.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 225,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-6. Sellers' total revenue would increase if the price",
                    "options": [
                        "increased from $4 to $6.",
                        "increased from $16 to $18.",
                        "decreased from $8 to $6.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increased from $4 to $6.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 226,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-6. Sellers' total revenue would increase if the price",
                    "options": [
                        "increased from $6 to $8.",
                        "decreased from $18 to $16.",
                        "decreased from $16 to $15.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 227,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-6. Which of the following price changes would result in no change in sellers' total revenue?",
                    "options": [
                        "The price increases from $6 to $9.",
                        "The price increases from $9 to $15.",
                        "The price decreases from $12 to $9.",
                        "The price decreases from $9 to $5."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The price decreases from $12 to $9.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 228,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-7. For prices above $8, demand is price",
                    "options": [
                        "elastic, and total revenue will rise as price rises.",
                        "inelastic, and total revenue will rise as price rises.",
                        "elastic, and total revenue will fall as price rises.",
                        "inelastic, and total revenue will fall as price rises."
                    ],
                    "answer": "elastic, and total revenue will fall as price rises.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 229,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-7. For prices below $8, demand is price",
                    "options": [
                        "elastic, and total revenue will rise as price rises.",
                        "inelastic, and total revenue will rise as price rises.",
                        "elastic, and total revenue will fall as price rises.",
                        "inelastic, and total revenue will fall as price rises."
                    ],
                    "answer": "inelastic, and total revenue will rise as price rises.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 230,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-8. For prices above $5, demand is price",
                    "options": [
                        "elastic, and raising price will increase total revenue.",
                        "inelastic, and raising price will increase total revenue.",
                        "elastic, and lowering price will increase total revenue.",
                        "inelastic, and lowering price will increase total revenue."
                    ],
                    "answer": "elastic, and lowering price will increase total revenue.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 231,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-8. For prices below $5, demand is price",
                    "options": [
                        "elastic, and raising price will increase total revenue.",
                        "inelastic, and raising price will increase total revenue.",
                        "elastic, and lowering price will increase total revenue.",
                        "inelastic, and lowering price will increase total revenue."
                    ],
                    "answer": "inelastic, and raising price will increase total revenue.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 232,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-9. Suppose this demand curve is a straight, downward-sloping line all the way from the horizontal intercept to the vertical intercept. We choose two prices, P1 and P2, and the corresponding quantities demanded, Q1 and Q2, for the purpose of calculating the price elasticity of demand. Also suppose P2 > P1. In which of the following cases could we possibly find that (i) demand is elastic and (ii) an increase in price from P1 to P2 causes an increase in total revenue?",
                    "options": [
                        "0 < P1 < P2 < $10.",
                        "$10 < P1 < P2 < $15.",
                        "P1 > $15.",
                        "None of the above is correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "None of the above is correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 233,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-9. If price increases from $10 to $15, total revenue will",
                    "options": [
                        "increase by $20, so demand must be inelastic in this price range.",
                        "increase by $5, so demand must be inelastic in this price range.",
                        "decrease by $20, so demand must be elastic in this price range.",
                        "decrease by $10, so demand must be elastic in this price range."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase by $20, so demand must be inelastic in this price range.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 234,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-9. A decrease in price from $15 to $10 leads to a",
                    "options": [
                        "decrease in total revenue of $10, so the price elasticity of demand is greater than 1 in this price range.",
                        "decrease in total revenue of $10, so the price elasticity of demand is less than 1 in this price range.",
                        "decrease in total revenue of $20, so the price elasticity of demand is less than 1 in this price range.",
                        "decrease in total revenue of $20, so demand is elastic in this price range."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease in total revenue of $20, so the price elasticity of demand is less than 1 in this price range.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 235,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-10. When the price is $30, total revenue is",
                    "options": [
                        "$3,000.",
                        "$5,000.",
                        "$7,000.",
                        "$9,000."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$9,000.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 236,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-10. When price falls from $50 to $40, demand is",
                    "options": [
                        "inelastic, since total revenue decreases from $8,000 to $5,000.",
                        "inelastic, since total revenue increases from $5,000 to $8,000.",
                        "elastic, since total revenue increases from $5,000 to $8,000.",
                        "unit elastic, since total revenue does not change."
                    ],
                    "answer": "elastic, since total revenue increases from $5,000 to $8,000.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 237,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-10. An increase in price from $20 to $30 would",
                    "options": [
                        "increase total revenue by $2,000.",
                        "decrease total revenue by $2,000.",
                        "increase total revenue by $1,000.",
                        "decrease total revenue by $1,000."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase total revenue by $1,000.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 238,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-10. An increase in price from $30 to $35 would",
                    "options": [
                        "increase total revenue by $250",
                        "decrease total revenue by $250.",
                        "increase total revenue by $500.",
                        "decrease total revenue by $500."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease total revenue by $250.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 239,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-11. Using the midpoint method, the price elasticity of demand between point A and point B is about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.33.",
                        "0.5.",
                        "2.0.",
                        "3.0."
                    ],
                    "answer": "3.0.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 240,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-11. Using the midpoint method, the price elasticity of demand between point C and point D is about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.29.",
                        "0.54.",
                        "1.86.",
                        "2.0."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.54.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 241,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-11. If the price falls from point A to point B, total revenue",
                    "options": [
                        "increases, and demand is price elastic.",
                        "decreases, and demand is price elastic.",
                        "increases, and demand is price inelastic.",
                        "decreases, and demand is price inelastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increases, and demand is price elastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 242,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-11. If the price rises from point D to point C, total revenue",
                    "options": [
                        "increases, and demand is price elastic.",
                        "decreases, and demand is price elastic.",
                        "increases, and demand is price inelastic.",
                        "decreases, and demand is price inelastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increases, and demand is price inelastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 243,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-12. If rectangle D is larger than rectangle A, then",
                    "options": [
                        "demand is elastic between prices P1 and P2.",
                        "a decrease in price from P2 to P1 will cause an increase in total revenue.",
                        "the magnitude of the percent change in price between P1 and P2 is smaller than the magnitude of the corresponding percent change in quantity demanded.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 244,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-12. Total revenue when the price is P1 is represented by the area(s)",
                    "options": [
                        "B + D.",
                        "A + B.",
                        "C + D.",
                        "D."
                    ],
                    "answer": "B + D.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 245,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Demand",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-12. Total revenue when the price is P2 is represented by the area(s)",
                    "options": [
                        "B + D.",
                        "A + B.",
                        "C + D.",
                        "D."
                    ],
                    "answer": "A + B.",
                    "explanation": ""
                }
            ]
        },
        "sector3": {
            "title": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "q_num": 1,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A key determinant of the price elasticity of supply is the",
                    "options": [
                        "time horizon.",
                        "income of consumers.",
                        "price elasticity of demand.",
                        "importance of the good in a consumer's budget."
                    ],
                    "answer": "time horizon.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 1,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A decrease in supply will cause the largest increase in price when",
                    "options": [
                        "both supply and demand are inelastic.",
                        "both supply and demand are elastic.",
                        "demand is elastic and supply is inelastic.",
                        "demand is inelastic and supply is elastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "both supply and demand are inelastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 2,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A key determinant of the price elasticity of supply is the",
                    "options": [
                        "number of close substitutes for the good in question.",
                        "extent to which buyers alter their quantities demanded in response to changes in prices.",
                        "length of the time period.",
                        "extent to which buyers alter their quantities demanded in response to changes in their incomes."
                    ],
                    "answer": "length of the time period.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 2,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A decrease in supply will cause the smallest increase in price when",
                    "options": [
                        "both supply and demand are inelastic.",
                        "demand is elastic and supply is inelastic.",
                        "both supply and demand are elastic.",
                        "demand is inelastic and supply is elastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "both supply and demand are elastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 3,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A key determinant of the price elasticity of supply is",
                    "options": [
                        "the ability of sellers to change the price of the good they produce.",
                        "the ability of sellers to change the amount of the good they produce.",
                        "how responsive buyers are to changes in sellers' prices.",
                        "the slope of the demand curve."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the ability of sellers to change the amount of the good they produce.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 3,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The discovery of a new hybrid wheat would increase the supply of wheat. As a result, wheat farmers would realize an increase in total revenue if the",
                    "options": [
                        "supply of wheat is elastic.",
                        "supply of wheat is inelastic.",
                        "demand for wheat is inelastic.",
                        "demand for wheat is elastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "demand for wheat is elastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 4,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The price elasticity of supply measures how much",
                    "options": [
                        "the quantity supplied responds to changes in input prices.",
                        "the quantity supplied responds to changes in the price of the good.",
                        "the price of the good responds to changes in supply.",
                        "sellers respond to changes in technology."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the quantity supplied responds to changes in the price of the good.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 4,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Because the demand for wheat tends to be inelastic, the development of a new, more productive hybrid wheat would tend to",
                    "options": [
                        "increase the total revenue of wheat farmers.",
                        "decrease the total revenue of wheat farmers.",
                        "decrease the demand for wheat.",
                        "decrease the supply of wheat."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease the total revenue of wheat farmers.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 5,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The price elasticity of supply measures how responsive",
                    "options": [
                        "sellers are to a change in price.",
                        "sellers are to a change in buyers' income.",
                        "buyers are to a change in production costs.",
                        "equilibrium price is to a change in supply."
                    ],
                    "answer": "sellers are to a change in price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 5,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Knowing that the demand for wheat is inelastic, if all farmers voluntarily did not plant wheat on 10 percent of their land, then",
                    "options": [
                        "consumers of wheat would buy more wheat.",
                        "wheat farmers would suffer a reduction in their total revenue.",
                        "wheat farmers would experience an increase in their total revenue.",
                        "the demand for wheat would decrease."
                    ],
                    "answer": "wheat farmers would experience an increase in their total revenue.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 6,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The price elasticity of supply measures how responsive",
                    "options": [
                        "equilibrium price is to equilibrium quantity.",
                        "sellers are to a change in buyers' income.",
                        "sellers are to a change in price.",
                        "consumers are to the number of substitutes."
                    ],
                    "answer": "sellers are to a change in price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 6,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose researchers at the University of Wisconsin discover a new vitamin that increases the milk production of dairy cows. If the demand for milk is relatively inelastic, the discovery will",
                    "options": [
                        "raise both price and total revenues.",
                        "lower both price and total revenues.",
                        "raise price and lower total revenues.",
                        "lower price and raise total revenues."
                    ],
                    "answer": "lower both price and total revenues.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 7,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A linear, upward-sloping supply curve has",
                    "options": [
                        "a constant slope and a changing price elasticity of supply.",
                        "a changing slope and a constant price elasticity of supply.",
                        "both a constant slope and a constant price elasticity of supply.",
                        "both a changing slope and a changing price elasticity of supply."
                    ],
                    "answer": "a constant slope and a changing price elasticity of supply.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 7,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that corn farmers want to increase their total revenue. Knowing that the demand for corn is inelastic, corn farmers should",
                    "options": [
                        "plant more corn so that they would be able to sell more each year.",
                        "increase spending on fertilizer in an attempt to produce more corn on the acres they farm.",
                        "reduce the number of acres on which they plant corn.",
                        "contribute to a fund that promotes technological advances in corn production."
                    ],
                    "answer": "reduce the number of acres on which they plant corn.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 8,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A key determinant of the price elasticity of supply is the time period under consideration. Which of the following statements best explains this fact?",
                    "options": [
                        "Supply curves are steeper over long periods of time than over short periods of time.",
                        "Buyers of goods tend to be more responsive to price changes over long periods of time than over short periods of time.",
                        "The number of firms in a market tends to be more variable over long periods of time than over short periods of time.",
                        "Firms prefer to change their prices in the short run rather than in the long run."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The number of firms in a market tends to be more variable over long periods of time than over short periods of time.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 8,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Good news for farming can be bad news for farmers because the",
                    "options": [
                        "supply curve for an individual farmer is usually perfectly elastic.",
                        "supply curve for an individual farmer is usually perfectly inelastic.",
                        "demand for basic foodstuffs is usually inelastic, meaning that factors that shift supply to the right decrease total revenues to sellers.",
                        "demand for basic foodstuffs is usually elastic, meaning that factors that shift supply to the right increase total revenues to sellers."
                    ],
                    "answer": "demand for basic foodstuffs is usually inelastic, meaning that factors that shift supply to the right decrease total revenues to sellers.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 9,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Some firms eventually experience problems with their capacity to produce output as their output levels increase. For these firms,",
                    "options": [
                        "market power is substantial.",
                        "supply is perfectly inelastic.",
                        "supply is more elastic at low levels of output and less elastic at high levels of output.",
                        "supply is less elastic at low levels of output and more elastic at high levels of output."
                    ],
                    "answer": "supply is more elastic at low levels of output and less elastic at high levels of output.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 9,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If soybean farmers know that the demand for soybeans is price inelastic, in order to increase their total revenues they should",
                    "options": [
                        "use more fertilizers and weed killers to increase their yields.",
                        "plant additional acres to increase their output.",
                        "reduce the number of acres they plant to decrease their output.",
                        "Both a and b are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "reduce the number of acres they plant to decrease their output.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 10,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Generally, a firm is more willing and able to increase quantity supplied in response to a price change when",
                    "options": [
                        "the relevant time period is short rather than long.",
                        "the relevant time period is long rather than short.",
                        "supply is inelastic.",
                        "the firm is experiencing capacity problems."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the relevant time period is long rather than short.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 10,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Farm programs that pay farmers not to plant crops on all their land",
                    "options": [
                        "hurt farmers by lowering their total revenue and hurt consumers by causing shortages of some food items.",
                        "help farmers by cutting costs, which helps consumers by lowering food prices.",
                        "help farmers by increasing total revenue in the market but hurt consumers by raising food prices.",
                        "help farmers directly since they receive government payments but have no real effects on consumers."
                    ],
                    "answer": "help farmers by increasing total revenue in the market but hurt consumers by raising food prices.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 11,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The price elasticity of supply along a typical supply curve is",
                    "options": [
                        "constant.",
                        "equal to zero.",
                        "higher at low levels of quantity supplied and lower at high levels of quantity supplied.",
                        "lower at low levels of quantity supplied and higher at high levels of quantity supplied."
                    ],
                    "answer": "higher at low levels of quantity supplied and lower at high levels of quantity supplied.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 11,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "There are fewer farmers in the United States today than 200 years ago because of",
                    "options": [
                        "improvements in farm technology.",
                        "increased government regulations in farming.",
                        "an elastic demand for food.",
                        "environmental programs designed to reduce soil erosion."
                    ],
                    "answer": "improvements in farm technology.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 12,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that two supply curves pass through the same point. One is steep, and the other is flat. Which of the following statements is correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "The flatter supply curve represents a supply that is inelastic relative to the supply represented by the steeper supply curve.",
                        "The steeper supply curve represents a supply that is inelastic relative to the supply represented by the flatter supply curve.",
                        "Given two prices with which to calculate the price elasticity of supply, that elasticity would be the same for both curves.",
                        "A decrease in demand will increase total revenue if the steeper supply curve is relevant, while a decrease in demand will decrease total revenue if the flatter supply cure is relevant."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The steeper supply curve represents a supply that is inelastic relative to the supply represented by the flatter supply curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 12,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "How did the farm population in the United States change between 1950 and today?",
                    "options": [
                        "It dropped from 10 million to fewer than 3 million people.",
                        "It dropped from 20 million to fewer than 5 million people.",
                        "It dropped from 30 million to just over 6 million people.",
                        "It increased from 10 million to almost 13 million people."
                    ],
                    "answer": "It dropped from 10 million to fewer than 3 million people.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 13,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price elasticity of supply is 1.5, and a price increase led to a 1.8% increase in quantity supplied, then the price increase is about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.67%.",
                        "0.83%.",
                        "1.20%.",
                        "2.70%."
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.20%.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 13,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Between 1950 and today there was a",
                    "options": [
                        "20 percent drop in the number of farmers, but farm output more than tripled.",
                        "30 percent drop in the number of farmers, but farm output more than tripled.",
                        "50 percent drop in the number of farmers, but farm output more than doubled.",
                        "70 percent drop in the number of farmers, but farm output more than doubled."
                    ],
                    "answer": "70 percent drop in the number of farmers, but farm output more than doubled.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 14,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price elasticity of supply is 0.2, and a price increase led to a 3% increase in quantity supplied, then the price increase is about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.07%.",
                        "0.60%.",
                        "6%.",
                        "15%."
                    ],
                    "answer": "15%.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 14,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "An advance in farm technology that results in an increased market supply is",
                    "options": [
                        "good for farmers because it raises prices for their products but bad for consumers because it raises prices consumers pay for food.",
                        "bad for farmers because total revenue will fall but good for consumers because prices for food will fall.",
                        "good for farmers because it raises prices for their products and also good for consumers because more output is available for consumption.",
                        "bad for farmers because total revenue will fall and bad for consumers because farmers will raise the price of food to increase their total revenue."
                    ],
                    "answer": "bad for farmers because total revenue will fall but good for consumers because prices for food will fall.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 15,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price elasticity of supply is 1.5, and a price increase led to a 3% increase in quantity supplied, then the price increase is about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.2%.",
                        "0.5%.",
                        "2.0%.",
                        "4.5%."
                    ],
                    "answer": "2.0%.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 15,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Scenario 5-2. The equilibrium price will",
                    "options": [
                        "increase in both the aged cheddar cheese and bread markets.",
                        "increase in the aged cheddar cheese market and decrease in the bread market.",
                        "decrease in the aged cheddar cheese market and increase in the bread market.",
                        "decrease in both the aged cheddar cheese and bread markets."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease in both the aged cheddar cheese and bread markets.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 16,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price elasticity of supply is 1.2, and a price increase led to a 5% increase in quantity supplied, then the price increase is about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.24%.",
                        "4.2%.",
                        "6%.",
                        "6.2%."
                    ],
                    "answer": "4.2%.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 16,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Scenario 5-2. The equilibrium quantity will",
                    "options": [
                        "increase in both the aged cheddar cheese and bread markets.",
                        "increase in the aged cheddar cheese market and decrease in the bread market.",
                        "decrease in the aged cheddar cheese market and increase in the bread market.",
                        "decrease in both the aged cheddar cheese and bread markets."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease in both the aged cheddar cheese and bread markets.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 17,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price elasticity of supply is 1.2, and price increased by 5%, quantity supplied would",
                    "options": [
                        "increase by 4.2%.",
                        "increase by 6%.",
                        "decrease by 4.2%.",
                        "decrease by 6%."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase by 6%.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 17,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Scenario 5-2. The change in equilibrium price will be",
                    "options": [
                        "greater in the aged cheddar cheese market than in the bread market.",
                        "greater in the bread market than in the aged cheddar cheese market.",
                        "the same in the aged cheddar cheese and bread markets.",
                        "Any of the above could be correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "greater in the aged cheddar cheese market than in the bread market.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 18,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price elasticity of supply is 0.8, and price increased by 5%, quantity supplied would",
                    "options": [
                        "increase by 4%.",
                        "increase by 6.25%.",
                        "decrease by 4%.",
                        "decrease by 6.25%."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase by 4%.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 18,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Scenario 5-2. The change in equilibrium quantity will be",
                    "options": [
                        "greater in the aged cheddar cheese market than in the bread market.",
                        "greater in the bread market than in the aged cheddar cheese market.",
                        "the same in the aged cheddar cheese and bread markets.",
                        "Any of the above could be correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "greater in the bread market than in the aged cheddar cheese market.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 19,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose the price elasticity of supply for candles is 0.3 in the short run and 1.2 in the long run. If an increase in the demand for candles causes the price of candles to increase by 36%, then the quantity supplied of candles will increase by about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.8% in the short run and 3.3% in the long run.",
                        "1.2% in the short run and 0.3% in the long run.",
                        "10.8% in the short run and 43.2% in the long run.",
                        "120% in the short run and 30% in the long run."
                    ],
                    "answer": "10.8% in the short run and 43.2% in the long run.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 19,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Scenario 5-2. Total consumer spending on aged cheddar cheese will",
                    "options": [
                        "increase, and total consumer spending on bread will increase.",
                        "increase, and total consumer spending on bread will decrease.",
                        "decrease, and total consumer spending on bread will increase.",
                        "decrease, and total consumer spending on bread will decrease."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease, and total consumer spending on bread will decrease.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 20,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose the price elasticity of supply for soccer balls is 0.3 in the short run and 1.2 in the long run. If an increase in the demand for soccer balls causes the price of soccer balls to increase by 20%, then the quantity supplied of soccer balls will increase by about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.67% in the short run and 0.17% in the long run.",
                        "3% in the short run and 1.2% in the long run.",
                        "6% in the short run and 24% in the long run.",
                        "66.7% in the short run and 16.7% in the long run."
                    ],
                    "answer": "6% in the short run and 24% in the long run.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 20,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Scenario 5-3. The equilibrium price will",
                    "options": [
                        "increase in both the milk and beef markets.",
                        "increase in the milk market and decrease in the beef market.",
                        "decrease in the milk market and increase in the beef market.",
                        "decrease in both the milk and beef markets."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase in both the milk and beef markets.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 21,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose the price elasticity of supply for minivans is 0.3 in the short run and 1.2 in the long run. If an increase in the demand for minivans causes the price of minivans to increase by 5%, then the quantity supplied of minivans will increase by about",
                    "options": [
                        "1.5% in the short run and 6% in the long run.",
                        "6% in the short run and 1.5% in the long run.",
                        "16.7% in the short run and 4.2% in the long run.",
                        "4.2% in the short run and 16.7% in the long run."
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.5% in the short run and 6% in the long run.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 21,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Scenario 5-3. The equilibrium quantity will",
                    "options": [
                        "increase in both the milk and beef markets.",
                        "increase in the milk market and decrease in the beef market.",
                        "decrease in the milk market and increase in the beef market.",
                        "decrease in both the milk and beef markets."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decrease in both the milk and beef markets.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 22,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Scenario 5-1. The price elasticity of supply for aged cheddar cheese could be",
                    "options": [
                        "-1.",
                        "0.",
                        "0.5.",
                        "1.5."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.5.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 22,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Scenario 5-3. The change in equilibrium price will be",
                    "options": [
                        "greater in the milk market than in the beef market.",
                        "greater in the beef market than in the milk market.",
                        "the same in the milk and beef markets.",
                        "Any of the above could be correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "greater in the milk market than in the beef market.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 23,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Scenario 5-1. The price elasticity of supply for bread could be",
                    "options": [
                        "-1.",
                        "0.",
                        "0.5.",
                        "1.5."
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.5.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 23,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Scenario 5-3. The change in equilibrium quantity will be",
                    "options": [
                        "greater in the milk market than in the beef market.",
                        "greater in the beef market than in the milk market.",
                        "the same in the milk and beef markets.",
                        "Any of the above could be correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "greater in the beef market than in the milk market.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 24,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-5. Which of the three supply curves represents the least elastic supply?",
                    "options": [
                        "supply curve A",
                        "supply curve B",
                        "supply curve C",
                        "There is no difference in the elasticity of the three supply curves."
                    ],
                    "answer": "supply curve A",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 24,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Scenario 5-3. Total consumer spending on milk will",
                    "options": [
                        "increase, and total consumer spending on beef will increase.",
                        "increase, and total consumer spending on beef will decrease.",
                        "decrease, and total consumer spending on beef will increase.",
                        "decrease, and total consumer spending on beef will decrease."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase, and total consumer spending on beef will decrease.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 25,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-5. Which of the three supply curves represents the most elastic supply?",
                    "options": [
                        "supply curve A",
                        "supply curve B",
                        "supply curve C",
                        "There is no difference in the elasticity of the three supply curves."
                    ],
                    "answer": "supply curve C",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 26,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 5-5. Along which of the supply curves does quantity supplied move proportionately more than the price?",
                    "options": [
                        "along supply curve B only",
                        "along supply curves B and C",
                        "along all three supply curves",
                        "None. Quantity supplied moves proportionately less than the price along all of the three supply curves."
                    ],
                    "answer": "None. Quantity supplied moves proportionately less than the price along all of the three supply curves.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 27,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A manufacturer produces 400 units when the market price of $10 per unit and produces 600 units when the market price is $12 per unit. Using the midpoint method, for this range of prices, the price elasticity of supply is about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.45.",
                        "2.0.",
                        "2.2.",
                        "200."
                    ],
                    "answer": "2.2.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 28,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "At a price of $1.00, a local coffee shop is willing to supply 100 cinnamon rolls per day. At a price of $1.20, the coffee shop would be willing to supply 150 cinnamon rolls per day. Using the midpoint method, the price elasticity of supply is about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.45",
                        "0.90",
                        "1.11",
                        "2.20"
                    ],
                    "answer": "2.20",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 29,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "At a price of $1.20, a local coffee shop is willing to supply 100 cinnamon rolls per day. At a price of $1.40, the coffee shop would be willing to supply 150 cinnamon rolls per day. Using the midpoint method, the price elasticity of supply is about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.15",
                        "0.375",
                        "2.5",
                        "2.60"
                    ],
                    "answer": "2.60",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 30,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "On a certain supply curve, one point is (quantity supplied = 200, price = $4.00) and another point is (quantity supplied = 250, price = $4.50). Using the midpoint method, the price elasticity of supply is about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.22.",
                        "0.53.",
                        "1.00.",
                        "1.89."
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.89.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 31,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "On a certain supply curve, one point is (quantity supplied = 200, price = $2.00) and another point is (quantity supplied = 250, price = $2.50). Using the midpoint method, the price elasticity of supply is about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.2.",
                        "0.5.",
                        "1.0.",
                        "2.5."
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.0.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 32,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Holding all other factors constant and using the midpoint method, if a candy manufacturer increases production by 20 percent when the market price of candy increases from $0.50 to $0.60, then supply is",
                    "options": [
                        "inelastic, since the price elasticity of supply is equal to .91.",
                        "inelastic, since the price elasticity of supply is equal to 1.1.",
                        "elastic, since the price elasticity of supply is equal to 0.91.",
                        "elastic, since the price elasticity of supply is equal to 1.1."
                    ],
                    "answer": "elastic, since the price elasticity of supply is equal to 1.1.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 33,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Holding all other factors constant and using the midpoint method, if a calculator manufacturer increases production from 40 to 50 units when price increases by 20 percent, then supply is",
                    "options": [
                        "inelastic, since the price elasticity of supply is equal to .91.",
                        "inelastic, since the price elasticity of supply is equal to 1.1.",
                        "elastic, since the price elasticity of supply is equal to 0.91.",
                        "elastic, since the price elasticity of supply is equal to 1.1."
                    ],
                    "answer": "elastic, since the price elasticity of supply is equal to 1.1.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 34,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that an increase in the price of melons from $1.30 to $1.80 per pound increases the quantity of melons that melon farmers produce from 1.2 million pounds to 1.6 million pounds. Using the midpoint method, what is the approximate value of the price elasticity of supply?",
                    "options": [
                        "0.67",
                        "0.89",
                        "1.00",
                        "1.13"
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.89",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 35,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "An increase in the price of cheese crackers from $2.25 to $2.45 per box causes suppliers of cheese crackers to increase their quantity supplied from 125 boxes per minute to 145 boxes per minute. Using the midpoint method, supply is",
                    "options": [
                        "elastic, and the price elasticity of supply is 1.74.",
                        "elastic, and the price elasticity of supply is 0.57.",
                        "inelastic, and the price elasticity of supply is 1.74.",
                        "inelastic, and the price elasticity of supply is 0.57."
                    ],
                    "answer": "elastic, and the price elasticity of supply is 1.74.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 36,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A bakery would be willing to supply 500 bagels per day at a price of $0.50 each. At a price of $0.80, the bakery would be willing to supply 1,100 bagels. Using the midpoint method, the price elasticity of supply for bagels is about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.62.",
                        "0.77.",
                        "1.24.",
                        "1.63."
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.63.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 37,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A bakery would be willing to supply 500 donuts per day at a price of $0.50 each. At a price of $0.80, the bakery would be willing to supply 1,100 donuts. Using the midpoint method, the price elasticity of supply for donuts is about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.62, and supply is elastic.",
                        "0.62, and supply is inelastic.",
                        "1.63, and supply is elastic.",
                        "1.63, and supply is inelastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.63, and supply is elastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 38,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In January the price of dark chocolate candy bars was $2.00, and Willy's Chocolate Factory produced 80 pounds. In February the price of dark chocolate candy bars was $2.50, and Willy's produced 110 pounds. In March the price of dark chocolate candy bars was $3.00, and Willy's produced 140 pounds. The price elasticity of supply of Willy's dark chocolate candy bars was about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.70 when the price increased from $2.00 to $2.50 and 0.76 when the price increased from $2.50 to $3.00.",
                        "0.88 when the price increased from $2.00 to $2.50 and 1.08 when the price increased from $2.50 to $3.00.",
                        "1.42 when the price increased from $2.00 to $2.50 and 1.32 when the price increased from $2.50 to $3.00.",
                        "1.50 when the price increased from $2.00 to $2.50 and 1.18 when the price increased from $2.50 to $3.00."
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.42 when the price increased from $2.00 to $2.50 and 1.32 when the price increased from $2.50 to $3.00.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 39,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In January the price of widgets was $1.00, and Wendy's Widgets produced 80 widgets. In February the price of widgets was $1.50, and Wendy's Widgets produced 110 widgets. In March the price of widgets was $2.00, and Wendy's Widgets produced 140 widgets. The price elasticity of supply of Wendy's Widgets was about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.79 when the price increased from $1.00 to $1.50 and 0.84 when the price increased from $1.50 to $2.00.",
                        "1.27 when the price increased from $1.00 to $1.50 and 1.19 when the price increased from $1.50 to $2.00.",
                        "0.79 when the price increased from $1.00 to $1.50 and 1.19 when the price increased from $1.50 to $2.00.",
                        "1.27 when the price increased from $1.00 to $1.50 and 0.84 when the price increased from $1.50 to $2.00."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.79 when the price increased from $1.00 to $1.50 and 0.84 when the price increased from $1.50 to $2.00.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 40,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "At price of $1.20, a local pencil manufacturer is willing to supply 150 boxes per day. At a price of $1.40, the manufacturer is willing to supply 170 boxes per day. Using the midpoint method, the price elasticity of supply is about",
                    "options": [
                        "2.0.",
                        "1.23.",
                        "1.00.",
                        "0.81."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.81.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 41,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "At price of $1.30 per pound, a local apple orchard is willing to supply 150 pounds of apples per day. At a price of $1.50 per pound, the orchard is willing to supply 170 pounds of apples per day. Using the midpoint method, the price elasticity of supply is about",
                    "options": [
                        "1.14.",
                        "1.00.",
                        "0.875.",
                        "0.50."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.875.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 42,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "At price of $1.25, a paper manufacturer is willing to supply 150 spiral notebooks per day. At a price of $1.50, the paper manufacturer is willing to supply 175 spiral notebooks per day. Using the midpoint method, the price elasticity of supply is about",
                    "options": [
                        "1.18.",
                        "1.00.",
                        "0.85.",
                        "0.25."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.85.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 43,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-13. Over which range is the supply curve in this figure the most elastic?",
                    "options": [
                        "$16 to $40",
                        "$40 to $100",
                        "$100 to $220",
                        "$220 to $430"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$16 to $40",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 44,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-13. Over which range is the supply curve in this figure the least elastic?",
                    "options": [
                        "$16 to $40",
                        "$40 to $100",
                        "$100 to $220",
                        "$220 to $430"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$220 to $430",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 45,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-13. Using the midpoint method, what is the price elasticity of supply between $16 and $40?",
                    "options": [
                        "0.125",
                        "0.86",
                        "1.0",
                        "2.5"
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.0",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 46,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-13. Using the midpoint method, what is the price elasticity of supply between $100 and $220?",
                    "options": [
                        "0.58",
                        "0.67",
                        "1.00",
                        "1.73"
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.58",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 47,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-14. Along which of these segments of the supply curve is supply least elastic?",
                    "options": [
                        "GH",
                        "CD",
                        "AC",
                        "AB"
                    ],
                    "answer": "GH",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 48,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-14. Along which of these segments of the supply curve is supply most elastic?",
                    "options": [
                        "AB",
                        "CD",
                        "DH",
                        "GH"
                    ],
                    "answer": "AB",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 49,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-14. Using the midpoint method, what is the price elasticity of supply between points A and B?",
                    "options": [
                        "2.33",
                        "1.0",
                        "0.43",
                        "0.1"
                    ],
                    "answer": "2.33",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 50,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-14. Using the midpoint method, what is the price elasticity of supply between points B and C?",
                    "options": [
                        "1.67",
                        "1.19",
                        "0.84",
                        "0.61"
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.19",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 51,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-14. Using the midpoint method, what is the price elasticity of supply between points C and D?",
                    "options": [
                        "0.21",
                        "0.29",
                        "0.73",
                        "1.36"
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.73",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 52,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-14. Using the midpoint method, what is the price elasticity of supply between points D and G?",
                    "options": [
                        "1.89",
                        "1.26",
                        "0.53",
                        "0.34"
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.53",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 53,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-15. Using the midpoint method, what is the price elasticity of supply between $4 and $6?",
                    "options": [
                        "0.75",
                        "1.00",
                        "1.20",
                        "1.25"
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.25",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 54,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-15. Using the midpoint method, what is the price elasticity of supply between $6 and $8?",
                    "options": [
                        "0.86",
                        "1.00",
                        "1.17",
                        "1.25"
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.17",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 55,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-16. Using the midpoint method, what is the price elasticity of supply between point A and point B?",
                    "options": [
                        "0.58",
                        "0.71",
                        "1.06",
                        "1.4"
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.71",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 56,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-16. Using the midpoint method, what is the price elasticity of supply between point B and point C?",
                    "options": [
                        "1.44",
                        "1.29",
                        "0.96",
                        "0.78"
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.78",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 57,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-16. If, holding the supply curve fixed, there were an increase in demand that caused the equilibrium price to increase from $6 to $8, then sellers' total revenue would",
                    "options": [
                        "increase.",
                        "decrease.",
                        "remain unchanged.",
                        "The effect on total revenue cannot be determined from the given information."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 58,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The supply of a good will be more elastic, the",
                    "options": [
                        "more the good is considered a luxury.",
                        "broader is the definition of the market for the good.",
                        "larger the number of close substitutes for the good.",
                        "longer the time period being considered."
                    ],
                    "answer": "longer the time period being considered.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 59,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In the long run, the quantity supplied of most goods",
                    "options": [
                        "will increase in almost all cases, regardless of what happens to price.",
                        "cannot respond at all to a change in price.",
                        "can respond to a change in price, but the change is almost always inconsequential.",
                        "can respond substantially to a change in price."
                    ],
                    "answer": "can respond substantially to a change in price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 60,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When a supply curve is relatively flat, the",
                    "options": [
                        "sellers are not at all responsive to a change in price.",
                        "equilibrium price changes substantially when the demand for the good changes.",
                        "supply is relatively elastic.",
                        "supply is relatively inelastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "supply is relatively elastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 61,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When a supply curve is relatively flat,",
                    "options": [
                        "sellers are not very responsive to changes in price.",
                        "supply is relatively inelastic.",
                        "supply is relatively elastic.",
                        "Both a and b are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "supply is relatively elastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 62,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "As price elasticity of supply increases, the supply curve",
                    "options": [
                        "becomes flatter.",
                        "becomes steeper.",
                        "becomes downward sloping.",
                        "shifts to the right."
                    ],
                    "answer": "becomes flatter.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 63,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If a 25% change in price results in a 40% change in quantity supplied, then the price elasticity of supply is about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.63, and supply is elastic.",
                        "0.63, and supply is inelastic.",
                        "1.60, and supply is elastic.",
                        "1.60, and supply is inelastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.60, and supply is elastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 64,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If a 15% change in price results in a 20% change in quantity supplied, then the price elasticity of supply is about",
                    "options": [
                        "1.33, and supply is elastic.",
                        "1.33, and supply is inelastic.",
                        "0.75, and supply is elastic.",
                        "0.75, and supply is inelastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "1.33, and supply is elastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 65,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the quantity supplied responds only slightly to changes in price, then",
                    "options": [
                        "supply is said to be elastic.",
                        "supply is said to be inelastic.",
                        "an increase in price will not shift the supply curve very much.",
                        "even a large decrease in demand will change the equilibrium price only slightly."
                    ],
                    "answer": "supply is said to be inelastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 66,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Frequently, in the short run, the quantity supplied of a good is",
                    "options": [
                        "impossible, or nearly impossible, to measure.",
                        "not very responsive to price changes.",
                        "determined by the quantity demanded of the good.",
                        "determined by psychological forces and other non-economic forces."
                    ],
                    "answer": "not very responsive to price changes.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 67,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price elasticity of supply for wheat is less than 1, then the supply of wheat is",
                    "options": [
                        "inelastic.",
                        "elastic.",
                        "unit elastic.",
                        "quite sensitive to changes in income."
                    ],
                    "answer": "inelastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 68,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If a 40% change in price results in a 25% change in quantity supplied, then the price elasticity of supply is about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.63, and supply is elastic.",
                        "0.63, and supply is inelastic.",
                        "1.60, and supply is elastic.",
                        "1.60, and supply is inelastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.63, and supply is inelastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 69,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If a 30 percent change in price causes a 15 percent change in quantity supplied, then the price elasticity of supply is about",
                    "options": [
                        "0.5, and supply is elastic.",
                        "0.5, and supply is inelastic.",
                        "2, and supply is inelastic.",
                        "2, and supply is elastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.5, and supply is inelastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 70,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If a 20% change in price results in a 15% change in quantity supplied, then the price elasticity of supply is about",
                    "options": [
                        "1.33, and supply is elastic.",
                        "1.33, and supply is inelastic.",
                        "0.75, and supply is elastic.",
                        "0.75, and supply is inelastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "0.75, and supply is inelastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 71,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If sellers respond to very small changes in price by adjusting their quantity supplied by extremely large amounts, the price elasticity of supply approaches",
                    "options": [
                        "zero, and the supply curve is horizontal.",
                        "zero, and the supply curve is vertical.",
                        "infinity, and the supply curve is horizontal.",
                        "infinity, and the supply curve is vertical."
                    ],
                    "answer": "infinity, and the supply curve is horizontal.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 72,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements is valid when supply is perfectly elastic at a price of $4?",
                    "options": [
                        "The elasticity of supply approaches infinity.",
                        "The supply curve is vertical.",
                        "At a price below $4, quantity supplied is infinite.",
                        "At a price above $4, quantity supplied is zero."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The elasticity of supply approaches infinity.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 73,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements is not valid when supply is perfectly elastic?",
                    "options": [
                        "The elasticity of supply approaches infinity.",
                        "The supply curve is horizontal.",
                        "Very small changes in price lead to very large changes in quantity supplied.",
                        "The time period under consideration is more likely a short period rather than a long period."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The time period under consideration is more likely a short period rather than a long period.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 74,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When supply is perfectly elastic, the value of the price elasticity of supply is",
                    "options": [
                        "0.",
                        "1.",
                        "greater than 0 and less than 1.",
                        "infinity."
                    ],
                    "answer": "infinity.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 75,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "As the price elasticity of supply approaches infinity, very small changes in price lead to",
                    "options": [
                        "very large changes in quantity supplied.",
                        "very small changes in quantity supplied.",
                        "no change in quantity supplied.",
                        "None of the above is correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "very large changes in quantity supplied.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 76,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price elasticity of supply for a good is equal to infinity, then the",
                    "options": [
                        "supply curve is vertical.",
                        "supply curve is horizontal.",
                        "supply curve also has a slope equal to infinity.",
                        "quantity supplied is constant regardless of the price."
                    ],
                    "answer": "supply curve is horizontal.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 77,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A manufacturer produces 1,000 units, regardless of the market price. For this firm, the price elasticity of supply is",
                    "options": [
                        "infinity.",
                        "zero.",
                        "one.",
                        "negative one."
                    ],
                    "answer": "zero.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 78,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If sellers do not adjust their quantity supplied at all in response to a change in price, the price elasticity of supply is",
                    "options": [
                        "zero, and the supply curve is horizontal.",
                        "zero, and the supply curve is vertical.",
                        "infinity, and the supply curve is horizontal.",
                        "infinity, and the supply curve is vertical."
                    ],
                    "answer": "zero, and the supply curve is vertical.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 79,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements is valid when the market supply curve is vertical?",
                    "options": [
                        "Market quantity supplied does not change when the price changes.",
                        "Supply is perfectly elastic.",
                        "An increase in market demand will increase the equilibrium quantity.",
                        "An increase in market demand will not increase the equilibrium price."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Market quantity supplied does not change when the price changes.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 80,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements is not valid when the market supply curve is vertical?",
                    "options": [
                        "Market quantity supplied does not change when the price changes.",
                        "Supply is perfectly inelastic.",
                        "An increase in market demand will increase the equilibrium quantity.",
                        "An increase in market demand will increase the equilibrium price."
                    ],
                    "answer": "An increase in market demand will increase the equilibrium quantity.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 81,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the quantity supplied is the same regardless of price, then supply is",
                    "options": [
                        "elastic.",
                        "perfectly elastic.",
                        "perfectly inelastic.",
                        "inelastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "perfectly inelastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 82,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If sellers do not adjust their quantities supplied at all in response to a change in price,",
                    "options": [
                        "advances in technology must be prevalent.",
                        "the time period under consideration must be very long.",
                        "supply is perfectly elastic.",
                        "supply is perfectly inelastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "supply is perfectly inelastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 83,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the price elasticity of supply is zero, then",
                    "options": [
                        "supply is more elastic than it is in any other case.",
                        "the supply curve is horizontal.",
                        "the quantity supplied is the same, regardless of price.",
                        "a change in demand will cause a relatively small change in the equilibrium price."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the quantity supplied is the same, regardless of price.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 84,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is an illustration of the market for original paintings by deceased artist Vincent Van Gogh? Price Price S D D Quantity Price Quantity Price D S S Quantity",
                    "options": [
                        "",
                        "S",
                        "",
                        "D",
                        "A",
                        "B",
                        "C",
                        "D"
                    ],
                    "answer": "S",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 85,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-17. Which of the following statements is not correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "Supply curve A is perfectly inelastic.",
                        "Supply curve B is perfectly elastic.",
                        "Supply curve C is unit elastic.",
                        "Supply curve D is more elastic than supply curve C."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Supply curve C is unit elastic.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 86,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-17. Which of the following statements is correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "Supply curve A is perfectly elastic.",
                        "Supply curve B is perfectly inelastic.",
                        "Supply curve C is more inelastic than supply curve D.",
                        "Supply curve D is unit elastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Supply curve C is more inelastic than supply curve D.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 87,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-18. Which supply curve is most likely relevant over a very long period of time?",
                    "options": [
                        "S1",
                        "S2",
                        "S3",
                        "All of the above are equally likely to be relevant over a very long period of time."
                    ],
                    "answer": "S3",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 88,
                    "topic": "The Elasticity Of Supply",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 5-18. Which supply curve represents perfectly inelastic supply?",
                    "options": [
                        "S1",
                        "S2",
                        "S3",
                        "None of the supply curves is perfectly inelastic."
                    ],
                    "answer": "S1",
                    "explanation": ""
                }
            ]
        }
    }
}
